<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>CARICOM on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/caricom/</link><description>Recent content in CARICOM on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/caricom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Heats Up, Trinidad PM Addresses Energy Week, Jamaica IMF Deal, and Cuba's Humanitarian Crisis Deepens</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with schools closing for election day, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM addresses Caribbean Energy Week, Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF $415M deal progresses, and Cuba&amp;rsquo;s crisis worsens as US tightens the screws.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, Barbados Election Heating Up, T&amp;T PM Blasts CARICOM, and Haiti Under Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF funds, Barbados gears up for February 11 election, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti&amp;rsquo;s leadership, and the T20 World Cup kicks off tomorrow. Your Caribbean regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election ONE WEEK Away, T20 World Cup Starts Friday, and the US Still Patrolling Caribbean Waters Like It's Their Pool</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados votes in 7 days with 93 candidates and Mottley going for a third term. The T20 World Cup starts Friday in India with West Indies facing Scotland. US military operations in the Caribbean continue dividing the region. Plus: Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF lifeline, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s police shooting scandal, and the CCJ President visits Barbados.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, US Tightens Visa Screws on Caribbean, and Trinidad Says 'We Didn't Do It'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF cash after Hurricane Melissa, the US cracks down on Caribbean birth tourism visas, and Trinidad keeps insisting it had nothing to do with the Venezuela operation. Your regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Daily Brief – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</guid><description>IMF approves US$415M emergency aid for Jamaica, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, Venezuela aftermath reshaping regional travel, West Indies cricket, and more across the islands!</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Feb 11, Trinidad PM Kamla Navigates CARICOM, Caribbean Airlines Restructures</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>PM Mottley calls snap election for February 11 seeking historic third term, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s Kamla Persad-Bissessar defends CARICOM stance, and Caribbean Airlines closes its Barbados hub.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Goes to Polls Feb 11, Trinidad's PM Kamla Warns About 'Divisiveness', Jamaica Gets $415M Hurricane Relief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley calls Barbados elections for February 11, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s new PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar navigates US-Venezuela tensions, Jamaica secures IMF emergency funding for Hurricane Melissa recovery, and Caribbean Airlines restructures its regional operations.</description></item></channel></rss>