<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Cricket on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cricket/</link><description>Recent content in Cricket on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cricket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monday Brief: Auditor General Goes Silent While Billions Vanish, 77 Cubans Screened for Trafficking, and Hetmyer Breaks a World Cup Record</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</guid><description>Christopher Ram questions whether the Auditor General is actually auditing anything, 77 Cubans are screened for suspected human trafficking, more than 20 homes bulldozed in Circuitville, and Hetmyer smashes the fastest WI fifty in T20 World Cup history.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Two Guyanese Boys Own de World Cup, But de Brief Want Talk About Auditor General</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates Hetmyer and Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s World Cup heroics, praises the Bayroc Stadium opening, and wonders why the Brief is obsessed with Christopher Ram.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: US Strikes Boats Near Venezuela, Jamaica Gets $415M Emergency IMF Loan, and T&amp;T Says Airspace is Fine</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US is blowing up boats in the Caribbean, Jamaica needs emergency cash after Hurricane Melissa, Trinidad says everything is normal (it&amp;#39;s not), and the T20 World Cup has kicked off.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election ONE WEEK Away, T20 World Cup Starts Friday, and the US Still Patrolling Caribbean Waters Like It's Their Pool</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados votes in 7 days with 93 candidates and Mottley going for a third term. The T20 World Cup starts Friday in India with West Indies facing Scotland. US military operations in the Caribbean continue dividing the region. Plus: Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF lifeline, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s police shooting scandal, and the CCJ President visits Barbados.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Countdown, Trinidad's Police Scandal, and Carnival Season Heats Up</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with Mottley seeking a historic third term, Trinidad reels from CCTV footage of a police shooting, Carnival season kicks into high gear, and West Indies prep for T20 World Cup. Your regional Caribbean news roundup.</description></item><item><title>Sunday's Guyana Brief - Hotels Multiply, Health Goes Digital, and Cricket Women Keep Winning</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Another US$18M hotel opens, your medical records go online, President Ali says cash grants aren&amp;rsquo;t sustainable (after promising one), Women&amp;rsquo;s cricket squad stays undefeated, and Fruta Conquerors lose their president after 11 months.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Hotels Mean JOBS, Women Cricketers Making Us PROUD, and Stop Complaining!</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Women&amp;rsquo;s T20 squad, defends the hotel boom, explains why digital health records are PROGRESS, and asks why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t just be happy for once.</description></item><item><title>Saturday's Guyana Brief: Toy Guns Guarding Your Groceries, Solar Power Rising, and Guyana Women Battle Jamaica Tonight!</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Security guards caught with toy guns at supermarkets, US$8.14M solar farm lights up Charity, GBTI launches private banking for the rich, and Guyana Women seek redemption against Jamaica under the lights!</description></item><item><title>Cricket Dreams: How Guyana's Women Are Rewriting Sports History</title><link>http://localhost:1313/magazine/magazine-cricket-dreams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/magazine/magazine-cricket-dreams/</guid><description>While politics divides, Guyana&amp;rsquo;s women&amp;rsquo;s cricket team unites. This is the story of how a group of determined athletes became the nation&amp;rsquo;s most powerful symbol of what we can achieve together.</description></item></channel></rss>