<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Elections on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/elections/</link><description>Recent content in Elections on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Heats Up, Trinidad PM Addresses Energy Week, Jamaica IMF Deal, and Cuba's Humanitarian Crisis Deepens</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with schools closing for election day, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM addresses Caribbean Energy Week, Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF $415M deal progresses, and Cuba&amp;rsquo;s crisis worsens as US tightens the screws.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Elections Feb 11, US Visa Crackdowns, Trinidad's AI Push, and Jamaica's IMF Return</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Regional roundup: Mia Mottley goes for third term, US tightens visa rules for pregnant travelers, Trinidad partners with Microsoft on AI, and Jamaica seeks IMF help again.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Feb 11, Trinidad PM Kamla Navigates CARICOM, Caribbean Airlines Restructures</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>PM Mottley calls snap election for February 11 seeking historic third term, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s Kamla Persad-Bissessar defends CARICOM stance, and Caribbean Airlines closes its Barbados hub.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Goes to Polls Feb 11, Trinidad's PM Kamla Warns About 'Divisiveness', Jamaica Gets $415M Hurricane Relief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley calls Barbados elections for February 11, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s new PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar navigates US-Venezuela tensions, Jamaica secures IMF emergency funding for Hurricane Melissa recovery, and Caribbean Airlines restructures its regional operations.</description></item></channel></rss>