<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Healthcare on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/healthcare/</link><description>Recent content in Healthcare on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Mortgages, Nurses, and the Brief's Selective Memory</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh is a retired accountant from Berbice, now living in Queens, New York. He reads the papers — especially the Chronicle — and provides his perspective.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Monday morning and the Brief leading with Azruddin showing up late. That&amp;rsquo;s the headline? A man who is US-indicted, facing extradition, and can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to arrive on time to his own hearing — and the Brief treating it like comedy instead of asking why the Opposition Leader has such contempt for the judicial process?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: The Government Building, Not Destroying — Read the Chronicle, Not the Obituaries</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh is a retired accountant from Berbice, now living in Queens, New York. He reads the papers himself — especially the Chronicle — and responds to the Brief&amp;rsquo;s coverage with his own perspective. He is unapologetically pro-government when the government deserves it.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Alright, alright. Everybody crying about Stabroek News like the whole country falling apart. You know what else happened this weekend? &lt;strong>A US$120 million training college opened in Port Mourant.&lt;/strong> Thirty-five young Guyanese already working offshore. Certified. Employed. Earning real money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: 'Budget 2026 Is What Development Looks Like — Take Notes!'</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the papers independently and finds plenty to celebrate: Budget 2026&amp;rsquo;s massive investments, a fancy new Georgetown hotel, record tourism numbers, and the UK rolling out the red carpet for Guyana. The opposition? Still complaining.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar and the Mystery of the Missing Medical Records</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>When Speedeet&amp;rsquo;s grandmother can&amp;rsquo;t find her medical file at the clinic, the two friends discover that going digital isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as pressing a button.</description></item><item><title>Sunday's Guyana Brief - Hotels Multiply, Health Goes Digital, and Cricket Women Keep Winning</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Another US$18M hotel opens, your medical records go online, President Ali says cash grants aren&amp;rsquo;t sustainable (after promising one), Women&amp;rsquo;s cricket squad stays undefeated, and Fruta Conquerors lose their president after 11 months.</description></item><item><title>🏆 Patriots Portfolio - Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-17-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-17-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Celebration of Guyanese Excellence&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-this-weeks-patriot-dr-goldenheart-perseverance">🌟 This Week&amp;rsquo;s Patriot: Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Healer Who Never Bills Twice&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-legend">The Legend&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Every week, Uncle Ramesh searches high and low for Guyanese who exemplify the True Patriot Spirit™ - that special combination of unwavering government support, photogenic community service, and the ability to appear at ribbon-cutting ceremonies on short notice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week, we celebrate &lt;strong>Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance&lt;/strong>, a physician whose dedication to healing is matched only by her dedication to praising every new government health initiative, regardless of whether the clinic has running water.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dr. Sharmila Persaud: From Berbice to Brain Surgery</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>A Weekly Profile of Guyanese Excellence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore, Dr. Sharmila Persaud is performing some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most complex brain surgeries. But every morning, she looks at a photo on her desk: her grandmother&amp;rsquo;s wooden house in Berbice, where she grew up without electricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-journey">The Journey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;People ask me how I got from there to here,&amp;rdquo; Dr. Persaud says, gesturing around her state-of-the-art operating suite. &amp;ldquo;I tell them: I got here because I started there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>