<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Daily Brief on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/categories/daily-brief/</link><description>Recent content in Daily Brief on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/categories/daily-brief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Ali Collects Medal in Brazil While Budget Debate Wreckage Still Smouldering</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your Tuesday rundown from all four papers. Grab your coffee, this one&amp;rsquo;s spicy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-ali-gets-medal-country-gets-more-promises">🏅 Ali Gets Medal, Country Gets More Promises&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>President Ali popped across to Boa Vista on Monday and came back wearing the &lt;strong>Medalha Forte São Joaquim&lt;/strong> — Roraima&amp;rsquo;s highest honour — presented by Governor Antonio Denarium. The Chronicle gave it the full red-carpet treatment, naturally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali talked about &amp;ldquo;removing barriers to trade, improving connectivity, and creating an enabling environment for private-sector engagement&amp;rdquo; with Brazil. You know, all the things we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about since approximately 1966.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Auditor General Goes Silent While Billions Vanish, 77 Cubans Screened for Trafficking, and Hetmyer Breaks a World Cup Record</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</guid><description>Christopher Ram questions whether the Auditor General is actually auditing anything, 77 Cubans are screened for suspected human trafficking, more than 20 homes bulldozed in Circuitville, and Hetmyer smashes the fastest WI fifty in T20 World Cup history.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Brief: Exxon Now Owns ALL Four Oil Ships, Finance Minister Drops Pablo Escobar Reference, and a Miracle Baby at GPHC</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</guid><description>ExxonMobil completes its FPSO collection like Pokémon cards, Dr. Singh invokes Pablo Escobar in Parliament, GPHC doctors save mother and baby from a rare bleeding disorder, and the Opposition Leader says the budget won&amp;#39;t lift anyone out of poverty. Happy Sunday, Guyana.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Saturday Brief: Opposition Leader Rips Budget, Secret Extradition Revealed, and Linden Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader Mohamed delivers maiden budget speech and it&amp;rsquo;s a SCORCHER, a secret US extradition request surfaces, Linden opens its shiny new stadium, Ali promises miners the moon (if they declare their gold), and the Windies take on Scotland in the T20 World Cup opener.</description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief - Venezuela Still Scary, MP Falls in Parliament, 53,000 Weed Plants Burned, and the Budget Debate Rolls On Like a Runaway Canter</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</guid><description>President Ali tells the army &amp;lsquo;don&amp;rsquo;t blink&amp;rsquo; on Venezuela, an MP fractures her ankle falling in Parliament, police burn 53,000 cannabis plants in Linden, Kaieteur calls the budget &amp;lsquo;matchless propaganda,&amp;rsquo; and Dem Boys Seh more road just means more traffic. Your 5-minute Friday news circus.</description></item><item><title>Thursday's Guyana Brief — Four Dead on Vessel, Mohameds Lose Court Fight, Opposition Leader Gets No Car or Security, and $2 Billion to Fix Stabroek Market</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</guid><description>Tragedy strikes at Water Street wharf as four crew members die from gas fumes. Chief Justice rules against Mohameds in extradition challenge. Government says Opposition Leader won&amp;#39;t get personal security or vehicle. Plus: $2B for Stabroek and Bourda markets, gold at $5,000/ounce, and Speaker Nadir&amp;#39;s war on press continues.</description></item><item><title>☕ Wednesday Brief: Budget Day 2 Turns Into WWE SmackDown, Speaker Nadir's Press Crackdown Gets EVERYBODY Vex, and the Oil Fund About to Get US$2.8 Billion It Won't Keep</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget Day 2 delivers absolute chaos as government and opposition clash over everything from sugar to Amerindians. Speaker Nadir&amp;rsquo;s media lockout draws fire from every direction. The Oil Fund expects US$2.8B this year — and critics say it&amp;rsquo;ll disappear just as fast. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, 9 million carbon credits, and the T20 World Cup starts Friday.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday's Guyana Brief — Budget Debate Opens With Animal Noises, Speaker Locks Out Press, and President Flies to Belize to Tell Them How Great Guyana Is</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</guid><description>The 2026 budget debate opened with heckling and bizarre animal noises, Speaker Nadir brought back COVID rules to limit journalists to five, Ali told Belize to follow Guyana&amp;rsquo;s lead on food security, WIN and APNU both trashed the budget for different reasons, and a beloved Rupununi tour guide was murdered over cattle rustling.</description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Budget Debate D-Day, Mohameds Ruling Today, and Georgetown Gets a Fancy New Hotel</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate opens in the National Assembly, the Acting CJ rules on the Mohameds extradition challenge TODAY, Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s newest hotel opens, Mashramani gets $120M, and cattle rustlers allegedly killed a Rupununi conservationist. Your Monday morning news circus from all four papers.</description></item><item><title>☕ Sunday Brief: Budget Debate Opens Monday, Cement Truck Kills on Demerara Bridge, and the Government Discovers 'Late Movers' Advantage'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate starts Monday while Finance Minister discovers Guyana has a &amp;rsquo;late movers&amp;rsquo; advantage&amp;rsquo; in oil. Meanwhile, an unlicensed driver kills someone on the Demerara Bridge and the opposition says Tabatinga school is nowhere near ready. Your 5-minute Sunday news circus.</description></item><item><title>☕ The Guyana Daily Brief – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-31/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath, Guyana-UK climate deals, ExxonMobil eyes Venezuela border waters, Bangladesh opening embassy in GT, fatal Demerara River Bridge crash, and more from all four papers!</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: GRA Officers Fired Over Mohamed Vehicle Transfers, RUSAL Returns, and Christopher Ram Prescribes Fiscal Ozempic</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</guid><description>GRA employees terminated for helping sanctioned businessman move vehicles, Russian aluminum company returns to Guyana, and Christopher Ram says the government needs appetite control for spending.</description></item><item><title>De Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your daily dose of Guyanese news, served with a side of pepper sauce&lt;/em> 🌶️&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-gra-officers-getting-lock-up-over-azruddin-mohameds-fancy-cars">💰 GRA Officers Getting Lock Up Over Azruddin Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s Fancy Cars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, well, well&amp;hellip; remember how everybody was wondering how certain vehicles was getting through customs smoother than a greased-up mango seed? The Guyana Revenue Authority done fire several officers and now they heading to court for AML/CFT violations connected to transferring vehicles from our favourite US-sanctioned businessman, Azruddin Mohamed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: The Fugitive is Official, Budget Bonanza Continues, and Mia Mottley Goes for the Three-Peat</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Azruddin Mohamed is now officially Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Opposition Leader despite US indictments. Meanwhile, Budget 2026 promises keep rolling out and Barbados prepares for another Mottley landslide.</description></item><item><title>The Guyana Daily Brief - Tuesday, January 27, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath: $1.588 trillion in promises, 15,000 house lots, a school for autistic children, and the opposition still can&amp;rsquo;t find the door to the National Assembly.</description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Budget Day Showdown, Opposition's 'Fugitive' Gets His Day, and Berbice Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the Super Bowl of Guyanese politics: Budget 2026 drops while the opposition elects an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive&amp;rsquo; as their leader. Plus hotels, stadiums, and that $100,000 cash grant everyone&amp;rsquo;s been waiting for.</description></item><item><title>Saturday Brief: D-Day for Opposition Leader Vote Tomorrow</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Parliament meets Monday to elect Opposition Leader as rights groups sound alarm, plus chikungunya alert, Women&amp;#39;s Chamber tackles care work, and more from Guyana&amp;#39;s newspapers</description></item><item><title>The Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader drama continues, Budget 2026 incoming, Barama drops $1 billion, and INTERPOL busts gold smuggling ring</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: US Ambassador Says Nadir Can Have His Opinion, APAD Warns Against Fugitive Opposition Leader, Tourism Minister Takes River Cruise</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</guid><description>US Ambassador Theriot diplomatically sidesteps the Speaker drama, APAD joins the chorus against electing Mohamed, Minister Rodrigues cruises the Demerara, and over 200 Guyanese now certified in fibre optics. Plus opposition visits Tabatinga school and finds four workers.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: Speaker Nadir Says Electing 'International Fugitive' Would Stain Parliament, 70kg Cocaine Bust, Belgium Wants to Build Our Ports</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Speaker Nadir drops the &amp;lsquo;international fugitive&amp;rsquo; bomb on WIN, 70kg of cocaine found in Parika, Belgium wants to help build our ports, IATA talks airport improvements, and AG Nandlall schools Charrandass on what &amp;lsquo;fugitive offender&amp;rsquo; actually means.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Opposition Leader Coming Monday, Police Academy Scandal, and Georgetown Is STILL a Dumpster Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader election finally set for Monday, Police Academy sexual exploitation scandal rocks the force, and Georgetown garbage crisis deepens as Mayor backs out of meeting.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: Opposition Leader Monday Showdown, Solar Power for Linden, and Georgetown's Garbage Emergency</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Speaker Nadir finally schedules Opposition Leader vote for Monday while calling candidate an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive.&amp;rsquo; Plus: Linden gets solar farms, Georgetown drowning in garbage, and the Mohameds saga continues. Your 5-minute news circus.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Cash Grants Are So Last Year, Georgetown Is a Dumpster Fire, and Teachers Want Answers</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute Guyanese news circus — now with 100% less cash grants&lt;/em> ☕🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-cash-grants-not-sustainable--president">💸 CASH GRANTS: &amp;ldquo;NOT SUSTAINABLE&amp;rdquo; — PRESIDENT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What Happened:&lt;/strong> President Ali declared that future cash grants are &amp;ldquo;not sustainable,&amp;rdquo; warning that &amp;ldquo;some people would use this as a political opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Backstory:&lt;/strong> Just one year ago, the government was &amp;ldquo;committed to making future cash grants.&amp;rdquo; What a difference 365 days makes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Math:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2025: &amp;ldquo;We are committed to future cash grants!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2026: &amp;ldquo;Cash grants are not sustainable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also 2026: Oil production approaching 1 million barrels per day.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dem Boys Seh:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;When election coming, cash grant sustainable. When election done, cash grant unsustainable. Is like magic — de money just disappear!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Former Finance Minister Admits Exxon Exploited Us, Venezuela Border Watch, and Pay-To-Party Culture</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</guid><description>Winston Jordan finally admits what everyone knew, PM Phillips says troops are ready for anything Venezuelan, and birthday parties now cost admission.</description></item><item><title>Sunday's Guyana Brief - Hotels Multiply, Health Goes Digital, and Cricket Women Keep Winning</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Another US$18M hotel opens, your medical records go online, President Ali says cash grants aren&amp;rsquo;t sustainable (after promising one), Women&amp;rsquo;s cricket squad stays undefeated, and Fruta Conquerors lose their president after 11 months.</description></item><item><title>Saturday's Guyana Brief: Toy Guns Guarding Your Groceries, Solar Power Rising, and Guyana Women Battle Jamaica Tonight!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Security guards caught with toy guns at supermarkets, US$8.14M solar farm lights up Charity, GBTI launches private banking for the rich, and Guyana Women seek redemption against Jamaica under the lights!</description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief - Oil Wells Racing to Empty, Speaker Races to India</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-friday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Guyana! ☕&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Friday, where our oil fields are being liquidated faster than a closing-down sale, our Speaker fled to India while Parliament remains closed, and Exxon&amp;rsquo;s 75% &amp;ldquo;expense deduction&amp;rdquo; makes Nigerian email scams look amateur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Today&amp;rsquo;s menu:&lt;/strong> The Great Oil Heist exposed (75% goes to &amp;ldquo;costs&amp;rdquo;), Speaker escapes to India during constitutional crisis, French Ambassador politely suggests democracy might be nice, Mashramani launches because at least we can party, and President Ali promises no Venezuela deals (this time he means it, promise).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🔍 [CRITICAL] Wednesday Brief: Guyanese Takes IICA Helm, Census Controversy, and Cybercrime Crackdown</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Muhammad Ibrahim becomes IICA Director-General, census data sparks housing debate, cybercrime law faces criticism, and AG slams courts for ignoring legislation.</description></item><item><title>🔍 [CRITICAL] Monday Brief: Crime Stats, Search &amp; Rescue Upgrade, and Traffic Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-monday-brief/</guid><description>Murders up 11% despite overall crime drop, new $123M search and rescue system launched, over 3,100 traffic offences in one week, and financial system reforms promised.</description></item></channel></rss>