<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Trinidad Carnival on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/trinidad-carnival/</link><description>Recent content in Trinidad Carnival on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/trinidad-carnival/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Carnival Tuesday Approaches, Barbados Cabinet Sworn In, and Maduro Pleads Not Guilty in New York</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Caribbean! 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carnival Tuesday is tomorrow in Trinidad, Barbados has a brand new cabinet, Maduro pleaded not guilty in New York, and the US is making it harder for Caribbean nationals to visit. Your Monday regional roundup.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-trinidad-jouvert-done-parade-of-the-bands-tomorrow">🎭 Trinidad: J&amp;rsquo;ouvert Done, Parade of the Bands Tomorrow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Carnival Monday is winding down in Trinidad after a J&amp;rsquo;ouvert that started before dawn and a full day of revelry through Port of Spain, Tunapuna, and beyond. Police confiscated an impressive collection of weapons during early morning exercises — because some people apparently think Carnival is a medieval tournament.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival Monday Madness, Barbados Swears In a Government, and Cuba Can't Catch a Break</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Caribbean! 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Carnival Monday in Trinidad, election aftermath in Barbados, and Cuba is still trying to keep the lights on. Your weekly regional roundup of who&amp;rsquo;s partying, who&amp;rsquo;s governing, and who&amp;rsquo;s wondering where the fuel went.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-trinidad-carnival-monday--jouvert-in-full-swing">🎭 Trinidad Carnival Monday — J&amp;rsquo;ouvert in Full Swing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Carnival Monday in Trinidad and the streets of Tunapuna are packed with revellers covered in paint, mud, and questionable life decisions. J&amp;rsquo;ouvert started before dawn and will not stop until Trinidad collectively decides it&amp;rsquo;s had enough — which historically takes about 48 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item></channel></rss>