<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Budget 2026 on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/budget-2026/</link><description>Recent content in Budget 2026 on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/budget-2026/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🇬🇾 Saturday Brief: Opposition Leader Rips Budget, Secret Extradition Revealed, and Linden Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader Mohamed delivers maiden budget speech and it&amp;rsquo;s a SCORCHER, a secret US extradition request surfaces, Linden opens its shiny new stadium, Ali promises miners the moon (if they declare their gold), and the Windies take on Scotland in the T20 World Cup opener.</description></item><item><title>👴🏾 Uncle Ramesh: Stadium Opening Day! PROGRESS You Can TOUCH! While Opposition Leader Talks Nonsense!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Bayroc Stadium opening, praises Ali&amp;rsquo;s mining support package, and has STRONG words about the Opposition Leader&amp;rsquo;s maiden speech.</description></item><item><title>Patriots Portfolio: Budget 2026 Deep Dive — Where Is the $1.588 Trillion Actually Going?</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Patriots Portfolio breaks down the biggest budget stories: the $1.588 trillion allocation, tourism boom, gold sector resurrection, cash grants debate, and what it all means for ordinary Guyanese trying to build wealth in the fastest-growing economy in the world.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take: The President Standing Strong While They Nitpick Everything</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens breaks down why President Ali&amp;rsquo;s GDF speech was exactly what Guyana needed, the budget debate critics have no alternative plan, tourism is booming, and the opposition should stop complaining and start contributing.</description></item><item><title>Thursday's Guyana Brief — Four Dead on Vessel, Mohameds Lose Court Fight, Opposition Leader Gets No Car or Security, and $2 Billion to Fix Stabroek Market</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</guid><description>Tragedy strikes at Water Street wharf as four crew members die from gas fumes. Chief Justice rules against Mohameds in extradition challenge. Government says Opposition Leader won&amp;#39;t get personal security or vehicle. Plus: $2B for Stabroek and Bourda markets, gold at $5,000/ounce, and Speaker Nadir&amp;#39;s war on press continues.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Thursday Response — 'This Government Building the Future While Opposition Playing Victim'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle (and the other papers) from Queens and explains why the PPP is building the future while the opposition focuses on everything except solutions.</description></item><item><title>☕ Wednesday Brief: Budget Day 2 Turns Into WWE SmackDown, Speaker Nadir's Press Crackdown Gets EVERYBODY Vex, and the Oil Fund About to Get US$2.8 Billion It Won't Keep</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget Day 2 delivers absolute chaos as government and opposition clash over everything from sugar to Amerindians. Speaker Nadir&amp;rsquo;s media lockout draws fire from every direction. The Oil Fund expects US$2.8B this year — and critics say it&amp;rsquo;ll disappear just as fast. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, 9 million carbon credits, and the T20 World Cup starts Friday.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Got a Plan fuh Everything and All Dem Could Do is Complain!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition still complaining while the government delivering 53,000 house lots, 9 million carbon credits, and a five-year sugar plan. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, Lady Jags scoring 14 goals, and Minister Browne put Dawn Hastings in she place.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Wednesday, February 4, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Wednesday February 4, 2026.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday's Guyana Brief — Budget Debate Opens With Animal Noises, Speaker Locks Out Press, and President Flies to Belize to Tell Them How Great Guyana Is</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</guid><description>The 2026 budget debate opened with heckling and bizarre animal noises, Speaker Nadir brought back COVID rules to limit journalists to five, Ali told Belize to follow Guyana&amp;rsquo;s lead on food security, WIN and APNU both trashed the budget for different reasons, and a beloved Rupununi tour guide was murdered over cattle rustling.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Cyaan See Progress If Yuh Put Blindfold Pon Dem Eye'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle cover to cover, watches the budget debate livestream from Queens, and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition opened with a gold-smuggling MP demanding mining transparency.</description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Budget Debate D-Day, Mohameds Ruling Today, and Georgetown Gets a Fancy New Hotel</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate opens in the National Assembly, the Acting CJ rules on the Mohameds extradition challenge TODAY, Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s newest hotel opens, Mashramani gets $120M, and cattle rustlers allegedly killed a Rupununi conservationist. Your Monday morning news circus from all four papers.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: 'Budget 2026 Is What Development Looks Like — Take Notes!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the papers independently and finds plenty to celebrate: Budget 2026&amp;rsquo;s massive investments, a fancy new Georgetown hotel, record tourism numbers, and the UK rolling out the red carpet for Guyana. The opposition? Still complaining.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Monday, February 2, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Monday February 2, 2026.</description></item><item><title>☕ Sunday Brief: Budget Debate Opens Monday, Cement Truck Kills on Demerara Bridge, and the Government Discovers 'Late Movers' Advantage'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate starts Monday while Finance Minister discovers Guyana has a &amp;rsquo;late movers&amp;rsquo; advantage&amp;rsquo; in oil. Meanwhile, an unlicensed driver kills someone on the Demerara Bridge and the opposition says Tabatinga school is nowhere near ready. Your 5-minute Sunday news circus.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh: Budget 2026 Is a Masterclass, the Development Bank Is Revolutionary, and the Brief Needs an Economics Lesson</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle, celebrates Budget 2026 and the new Development Bank, and wonders why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t see progress when it&amp;rsquo;s staring them in the face.</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Development Bank Loans, Mash Prep, and Why Big People Love de Word 'Ambitious'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar try to understand interest-free loans, wonder who is paying for Mash costumes, and discover that big people use de word &amp;lsquo;ambitious&amp;rsquo; for everything.</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: GRA Officers Fired Over Mohamed Vehicle Transfers, RUSAL Returns, and Christopher Ram Prescribes Fiscal Ozempic</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</guid><description>GRA employees terminated for helping sanctioned businessman move vehicles, Russian aluminum company returns to Guyana, and Christopher Ram says the government needs appetite control for spending.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: GRA Doing Its Job, RUSAL Means JOBS, and Christopher Ram Needs to Relax</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens explains why GRA firing corrupt officers is GOOD news, RUSAL returning means JOBS for Linden, and Christopher Ram should let the government cook.</description></item><item><title>De Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your daily dose of Guyanese news, served with a side of pepper sauce&lt;/em> 🌶️&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-gra-officers-getting-lock-up-over-azruddin-mohameds-fancy-cars">💰 GRA Officers Getting Lock Up Over Azruddin Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s Fancy Cars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, well, well&amp;hellip; remember how everybody was wondering how certain vehicles was getting through customs smoother than a greased-up mango seed? The Guyana Revenue Authority done fire several officers and now they heading to court for AML/CFT violations connected to transferring vehicles from our favourite US-sanctioned businessman, Azruddin Mohamed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>A Pro-Government Perspective from Queens, NY&lt;/em> 🗽🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="nephew-and-niece-dem">Nephew and Niece Dem,&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Greetings from Queens where the cold biting but my heart warm from reading about all the good things happening back home!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me tell you, I just finish reading through the Budget 2026 details and I nearly fall off me chair with joy! &lt;strong>$1.558 TRILLION dollars!&lt;/strong> That is the biggest budget in Guyana history! And what the critics have to say? &amp;ldquo;Rich getting richer.&amp;rdquo; Eh-eh! When the country was poor and nothing wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening, dem same people was complaining. Now we building and spending, and dem still complaining!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: The Brief Still Can't Give Credit Where Credit Due!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh responds to The Brief&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Budget 2026 and the Opposition Leader election from his couch in Queens, NY.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: The Fugitive is Official, Budget Bonanza Continues, and Mia Mottley Goes for the Three-Peat</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Azruddin Mohamed is now officially Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Opposition Leader despite US indictments. Meanwhile, Budget 2026 promises keep rolling out and Barbados prepares for another Mottley landslide.</description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Budget Day Showdown, Opposition's 'Fugitive' Gets His Day, and Berbice Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the Super Bowl of Guyanese politics: Budget 2026 drops while the opposition elects an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive&amp;rsquo; as their leader. Plus hotels, stadiums, and that $100,000 cash grant everyone&amp;rsquo;s been waiting for.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: BUDGET 2026 IS HERE! $100,000 For EVERYBODY While Opposition Busy Electing Fugitives!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates Budget 2026 and the $100,000 cash grant while questioning why the opposition is electing a man facing US extradition charges.</description></item><item><title>The Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader drama continues, Budget 2026 incoming, Barama drops $1 billion, and INTERPOL busts gold smuggling ring</description></item></channel></rss>