<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Votes Tomorrow, T&amp;T PM Talks Energy, and Jamaica Mourns 'Cat' Coore</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your daily Caribbean roundup — what&amp;rsquo;s happening across the region.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-barbados-election-eve">🗳️ Barbados: Election Eve&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Barbados goes to the polls TOMORROW&lt;/strong> (Wednesday, February 11). Schools will be closed to facilitate voting. PM Mia Mottley&amp;rsquo;s Barbados Labour Party faces what observers say is the most competitive election in years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Commonwealth has deployed election observers. Meanwhile, PM Mottley made headlines by slamming opposition figure Ralph Thorne&amp;rsquo;s interview with a Trinidad media outlet, suggesting external interference. Trinidad PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar has denied that her UNC party is trying to influence the Barbados result.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Ali Collects Medal in Brazil While Budget Debate Wreckage Still Smouldering</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your Tuesday rundown from all four papers. Grab your coffee, this one&amp;rsquo;s spicy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-ali-gets-medal-country-gets-more-promises">🏅 Ali Gets Medal, Country Gets More Promises&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>President Ali popped across to Boa Vista on Monday and came back wearing the &lt;strong>Medalha Forte São Joaquim&lt;/strong> — Roraima&amp;rsquo;s highest honour — presented by Governor Antonio Denarium. The Chronicle gave it the full red-carpet treatment, naturally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ali talked about &amp;ldquo;removing barriers to trade, improving connectivity, and creating an enabling environment for private-sector engagement&amp;rdquo; with Brazil. You know, all the things we&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about since approximately 1966.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Dey Giving de Man Medal and All-You Still Complaining?</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-10-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh read de papers from Brooklyn dis morning and he got PLENTY to say.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Eh-eh! So de President gone Brazil, get de highest honour from Roraima state, talk about trade and food security and energy cooperation — and all-you STILL finding fault? De man building bridges — LITERAL bridges — between two countries and de opposition side chatting bout &amp;ldquo;we heard this before.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know what I hearing from Lethem side? People EXCITED. Brazilian business people coming over, Guyanese going across. Dat is REAL economic activity, not paper talk. When last time de opposition build a relationship with ANYBODY? Dey can&amp;rsquo;t even get along with deyself, much less a whole country.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Heats Up, Trinidad PM Addresses Energy Week, Jamaica IMF Deal, and Cuba's Humanitarian Crisis Deepens</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with schools closing for election day, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM addresses Caribbean Energy Week, Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF $415M deal progresses, and Cuba&amp;rsquo;s crisis worsens as US tightens the screws.</description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Auditor General Goes Silent While Billions Vanish, 77 Cubans Screened for Trafficking, and Hetmyer Breaks a World Cup Record</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</guid><description>Christopher Ram questions whether the Auditor General is actually auditing anything, 77 Cubans are screened for suspected human trafficking, more than 20 homes bulldozed in Circuitville, and Hetmyer smashes the fastest WI fifty in T20 World Cup history.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Two Guyanese Boys Own de World Cup, But de Brief Want Talk About Auditor General</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates Hetmyer and Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s World Cup heroics, praises the Bayroc Stadium opening, and wonders why the Brief is obsessed with Christopher Ram.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: US Strikes Boats Near Venezuela, Jamaica Gets $415M Emergency IMF Loan, and T&amp;T Says Airspace is Fine</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US is blowing up boats in the Caribbean, Jamaica needs emergency cash after Hurricane Melissa, Trinidad says everything is normal (it&amp;#39;s not), and the T20 World Cup has kicked off.</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Exxon Collecting Ships Like Sticker Book</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>De boys at the rum shop react to Exxon owning all four FPSOs, Dr. Singh&amp;#39;s Pablo Escobar moment, and the budget debate that was better than any movie.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: The Biggest Ship in the Sea</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar visit the waterfront and learn about the giant ships pumping Guyana&amp;#39;s oil — and ask the questions that matter.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Brief: Exxon Now Owns ALL Four Oil Ships, Finance Minister Drops Pablo Escobar Reference, and a Miracle Baby at GPHC</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</guid><description>ExxonMobil completes its FPSO collection like Pokémon cards, Dr. Singh invokes Pablo Escobar in Parliament, GPHC doctors save mother and baby from a rare bleeding disorder, and the Opposition Leader says the budget won&amp;#39;t lift anyone out of poverty. Happy Sunday, Guyana.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Dem Cyant See Progress Even When It Hit Dem in de Face</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Sunday papers and explains why the opposition can&amp;#39;t recognise progress even when it building a school next to them.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Sunday February 8, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute YouTube scripts for Speedeet &amp;amp; Wilar — Sunday February 8, 2026</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Saturday Brief: Opposition Leader Rips Budget, Secret Extradition Revealed, and Linden Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader Mohamed delivers maiden budget speech and it&amp;rsquo;s a SCORCHER, a secret US extradition request surfaces, Linden opens its shiny new stadium, Ali promises miners the moon (if they declare their gold), and the Windies take on Scotland in the T20 World Cup opener.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item><item><title>🎬 YouTube Scripts — Saturday, February 7, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts covering the Opposition Leader&amp;rsquo;s budget attack, secret extradition, Bayroc Stadium, small miners, and T20 World Cup.</description></item><item><title>🎯 Bounty Board — Saturday, February 7, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-bounty-board/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-bounty-board/</guid><description>Community events, deadlines, and happenings across Guyana! Bayroc Stadium opening, T20 World Cup schedule, Mashramani calendar, Elite League Cup, blood drive, and more!</description></item><item><title>👴🏾 Uncle Ramesh: Stadium Opening Day! PROGRESS You Can TOUCH! While Opposition Leader Talks Nonsense!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Bayroc Stadium opening, praises Ali&amp;rsquo;s mining support package, and has STRONG words about the Opposition Leader&amp;rsquo;s maiden speech.</description></item><item><title>💅 Bam-Bam Sally's Rumor Mill — Saturday, February 7, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-bam-bam-sally/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-bam-bam-sally/</guid><description>Bam-Bam Sally back with de freshest fictional gossip! Carnival costumes, stadium VIP passes, mining camp drama, and who wedding get postpone AGAIN!</description></item><item><title>🚛 Back-a-Truck — Saturday, February 7, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-back-a-truck/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-back-a-truck/</guid><description>De people&amp;rsquo;s marketplace! Fictional buy, sell, trade, and barter from all corners of Guyana. Back-a-truck and come see wha we got!</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, Barbados Election Heating Up, T&amp;T PM Blasts CARICOM, and Haiti Under Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF funds, Barbados gears up for February 11 election, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti&amp;rsquo;s leadership, and the T20 World Cup kicks off tomorrow. Your Caribbean regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>DJ Roadblock's Friday Traffic Report: More Road, More Traffic, More Vex</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-dj-roadblock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-dj-roadblock/</guid><description>DJ Roadblock brings you the Friday traffic chaos report — Dem Boys nailed it: more road just means more traffic. Plus the Eccles roundabout is still a parking lot, and the East Bank corridor has drivers questioning their life choices.</description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief - Venezuela Still Scary, MP Falls in Parliament, 53,000 Weed Plants Burned, and the Budget Debate Rolls On Like a Runaway Canter</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</guid><description>President Ali tells the army &amp;lsquo;don&amp;rsquo;t blink&amp;rsquo; on Venezuela, an MP fractures her ankle falling in Parliament, police burn 53,000 cannabis plants in Linden, Kaieteur calls the budget &amp;lsquo;matchless propaganda,&amp;rsquo; and Dem Boys Seh more road just means more traffic. Your 5-minute Friday news circus.</description></item><item><title>Patriots Portfolio: Budget 2026 Deep Dive — Where Is the $1.588 Trillion Actually Going?</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Patriots Portfolio breaks down the biggest budget stories: the $1.588 trillion allocation, tourism boom, gold sector resurrection, cash grants debate, and what it all means for ordinary Guyanese trying to build wealth in the fastest-growing economy in the world.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take: The President Standing Strong While They Nitpick Everything</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens breaks down why President Ali&amp;rsquo;s GDF speech was exactly what Guyana needed, the budget debate critics have no alternative plan, tourism is booming, and the opposition should stop complaining and start contributing.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>Thursday's Guyana Brief — Four Dead on Vessel, Mohameds Lose Court Fight, Opposition Leader Gets No Car or Security, and $2 Billion to Fix Stabroek Market</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-daily-brief/</guid><description>Tragedy strikes at Water Street wharf as four crew members die from gas fumes. Chief Justice rules against Mohameds in extradition challenge. Government says Opposition Leader won&amp;#39;t get personal security or vehicle. Plus: $2B for Stabroek and Bourda markets, gold at $5,000/ounce, and Speaker Nadir&amp;#39;s war on press continues.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Thursday Response — 'This Government Building the Future While Opposition Playing Victim'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle (and the other papers) from Queens and explains why the PPP is building the future while the opposition focuses on everything except solutions.</description></item><item><title>☕ Wednesday Brief: Budget Day 2 Turns Into WWE SmackDown, Speaker Nadir's Press Crackdown Gets EVERYBODY Vex, and the Oil Fund About to Get US$2.8 Billion It Won't Keep</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget Day 2 delivers absolute chaos as government and opposition clash over everything from sugar to Amerindians. Speaker Nadir&amp;rsquo;s media lockout draws fire from every direction. The Oil Fund expects US$2.8B this year — and critics say it&amp;rsquo;ll disappear just as fast. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, 9 million carbon credits, and the T20 World Cup starts Friday.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election ONE WEEK Away, T20 World Cup Starts Friday, and the US Still Patrolling Caribbean Waters Like It's Their Pool</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados votes in 7 days with 93 candidates and Mottley going for a third term. The T20 World Cup starts Friday in India with West Indies facing Scotland. US military operations in the Caribbean continue dividing the region. Plus: Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF lifeline, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s police shooting scandal, and the CCJ President visits Barbados.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Got a Plan fuh Everything and All Dem Could Do is Complain!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition still complaining while the government delivering 53,000 house lots, 9 million carbon credits, and a five-year sugar plan. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, Lady Jags scoring 14 goals, and Minister Browne put Dawn Hastings in she place.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Wednesday, February 4, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Wednesday February 4, 2026.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — US Warships Still Blowing Up Boats, Barbados Heads to Polls, Jamaica Gets IMF Lifeline, and the Region Wonders What Happened to Sovereignty</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US military campaign in Caribbean waters has killed over 117 people, Barbados elections are 8 days away, Jamaica secured $415M in IMF emergency aid, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM praised the boat strikes, and CARICOM can&amp;rsquo;t agree on anything except that things are complicated.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday's Guyana Brief — Budget Debate Opens With Animal Noises, Speaker Locks Out Press, and President Flies to Belize to Tell Them How Great Guyana Is</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-daily-brief/</guid><description>The 2026 budget debate opened with heckling and bizarre animal noises, Speaker Nadir brought back COVID rules to limit journalists to five, Ali told Belize to follow Guyana&amp;rsquo;s lead on food security, WIN and APNU both trashed the budget for different reasons, and a beloved Rupununi tour guide was murdered over cattle rustling.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Cyaan See Progress If Yuh Put Blindfold Pon Dem Eye'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle cover to cover, watches the budget debate livestream from Queens, and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition opened with a gold-smuggling MP demanding mining transparency.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Tuesday February 3, 2026 Daily Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s Daily Brief covering budget debates, Speaker media lockout, and Ali in Belize.</description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Budget Debate D-Day, Mohameds Ruling Today, and Georgetown Gets a Fancy New Hotel</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-monday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate opens in the National Assembly, the Acting CJ rules on the Mohameds extradition challenge TODAY, Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s newest hotel opens, Mashramani gets $120M, and cattle rustlers allegedly killed a Rupununi conservationist. Your Monday morning news circus from all four papers.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Countdown, Trinidad's Police Scandal, and Carnival Season Heats Up</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with Mottley seeking a historic third term, Trinidad reels from CCTV footage of a police shooting, Carnival season kicks into high gear, and West Indies prep for T20 World Cup. Your regional Caribbean news roundup.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Mango Tree War</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Everybody on Pike Street know dat de BEST julie mango tree belong to Miss Doreen. Everybody also know dat Miss Doreen does guard dem mango like gold. So when Speedeet come up wid a plan to &amp;rsquo;liberate&amp;rsquo; some mango&amp;hellip; well, yuh know how DIS gon end.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: 'Budget 2026 Is What Development Looks Like — Take Notes!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the papers independently and finds plenty to celebrate: Budget 2026&amp;rsquo;s massive investments, a fancy new Georgetown hotel, record tourism numbers, and the UK rolling out the red carpet for Guyana. The opposition? Still complaining.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Monday, February 2, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Monday February 2, 2026.</description></item><item><title>☕ Sunday Brief: Budget Debate Opens Monday, Cement Truck Kills on Demerara Bridge, and the Government Discovers 'Late Movers' Advantage'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate starts Monday while Finance Minister discovers Guyana has a &amp;rsquo;late movers&amp;rsquo; advantage&amp;rsquo; in oil. Meanwhile, an unlicensed driver kills someone on the Demerara Bridge and the opposition says Tabatinga school is nowhere near ready. Your 5-minute Sunday news circus.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh: Budget 2026 Is a Masterclass, the Development Bank Is Revolutionary, and the Brief Needs an Economics Lesson</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle, celebrates Budget 2026 and the new Development Bank, and wonders why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t see progress when it&amp;rsquo;s staring them in the face.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, US Tightens Visa Screws on Caribbean, and Trinidad Says 'We Didn't Do It'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF cash after Hurricane Melissa, the US cracks down on Caribbean birth tourism visas, and Trinidad keeps insisting it had nothing to do with the Venezuela operation. Your regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Development Bank Loans, Mash Prep, and Why Big People Love de Word 'Ambitious'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar try to understand interest-free loans, wonder who is paying for Mash costumes, and discover that big people use de word &amp;lsquo;ambitious&amp;rsquo; for everything.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Mash Costume Crisis</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar try to figure out Mashramani costumes on a budget of exactly zero dollars. Wilar has a plan. Speedeet has doubts. Miss Sharma&amp;rsquo;s clothesline has feathers.</description></item><item><title>☕ The Guyana Daily Brief – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-31/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath, Guyana-UK climate deals, ExxonMobil eyes Venezuela border waters, Bangladesh opening embassy in GT, fatal Demerara River Bridge crash, and more from all four papers!</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh Responds – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-31/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh breaks down Budget 2026, the UK climate partnership, ExxonMobil&amp;#39;s production records, and reminds you WHY the PPP is the best thing since cook-up rice.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Daily Brief – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</guid><description>IMF approves US$415M emergency aid for Jamaica, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, Venezuela aftermath reshaping regional travel, West Indies cricket, and more across the islands!</description></item><item><title>🎬 YouTube Scripts – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/youtube-scripts-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/youtube-scripts-2026-01-31/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute YouTube scripts for The Guyana Daily Brief — Saturday, January 31, 2026</description></item><item><title>🎯 The Bounty Board – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/bounty-board-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/bounty-board-2026-01-31/</guid><description>Community notices, events, and happenings across Guyana! Your one-stop bulletin board for what&amp;#39;s going on!</description></item><item><title>📢 Bam-Bam Sally's Rumor Mill – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/bam-bam-sally-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/bam-bam-sally-2026-01-31/</guid><description>If yuh ain&amp;#39;t hear it from me, it ain&amp;#39;t worth hearing! Bam-Bam Sally got de HOT tea to close out January 2026!</description></item><item><title>🚛 Back-a-Truck – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/back-a-truck-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/back-a-truck-2026-01-31/</guid><description>De people&amp;#39;s marketplace! Fictional buy, sell, trade, and barter from all corners of Guyana. Back-a-truck and come see wha we got!</description></item><item><title>🚗 DJ Roadblock Traffic Report - Friday, January 30, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-dj-roadblock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-dj-roadblock/</guid><description>DJ Roadblock with your Friday traffic update - Stanleytown bridge delays, Eccles roundabout chaos, and weekend getaway tips.</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: GRA Officers Fired Over Mohamed Vehicle Transfers, RUSAL Returns, and Christopher Ram Prescribes Fiscal Ozempic</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</guid><description>GRA employees terminated for helping sanctioned businessman move vehicles, Russian aluminum company returns to Guyana, and Christopher Ram says the government needs appetite control for spending.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: GRA Doing Its Job, RUSAL Means JOBS, and Christopher Ram Needs to Relax</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens explains why GRA firing corrupt officers is GOOD news, RUSAL returning means JOBS for Linden, and Christopher Ram should let the government cook.</description></item><item><title>🦅 Patriots Portfolio - Friday, January 30, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>Your weekly guide to understanding Guyana&amp;#39;s economic developments and investment landscape.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your regional roundup from across the Caribbean&lt;/em> 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-jamaica-gets-us415-million-imf-emergency-loan">🇯🇲 Jamaica Gets US$415 Million IMF Emergency Loan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The IMF Executive Board has approved Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s request for emergency financial assistance of approximately &lt;strong>US$415 million&lt;/strong> to help meet urgent balance-of-payments needs. This comes as the region continues to navigate economic pressures from various global factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s Finance Minister is expected to outline how these funds will be deployed to stabilize the economy and protect vulnerable populations. The country has been a model for IMF structural adjustment programs in the past, but this emergency assistance signals ongoing challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>De Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your daily dose of Guyanese news, served with a side of pepper sauce&lt;/em> 🌶️&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-gra-officers-getting-lock-up-over-azruddin-mohameds-fancy-cars">💰 GRA Officers Getting Lock Up Over Azruddin Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s Fancy Cars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, well, well&amp;hellip; remember how everybody was wondering how certain vehicles was getting through customs smoother than a greased-up mango seed? The Guyana Revenue Authority done fire several officers and now they heading to court for AML/CFT violations connected to transferring vehicles from our favourite US-sanctioned businessman, Azruddin Mohamed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>A Pro-Government Perspective from Queens, NY&lt;/em> 🗽🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="nephew-and-niece-dem">Nephew and Niece Dem,&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Greetings from Queens where the cold biting but my heart warm from reading about all the good things happening back home!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me tell you, I just finish reading through the Budget 2026 details and I nearly fall off me chair with joy! &lt;strong>$1.558 TRILLION dollars!&lt;/strong> That is the biggest budget in Guyana history! And what the critics have to say? &amp;ldquo;Rich getting richer.&amp;rdquo; Eh-eh! When the country was poor and nothing wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening, dem same people was complaining. Now we building and spending, and dem still complaining!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Mottley's Three-Peat, US Visa Crackdowns, and Airlines in Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11, Caribbean faces stricter US visa rules, and airlines are cutting routes left and right.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: The Brief Still Can't Give Credit Where Credit Due!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh responds to The Brief&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Budget 2026 and the Opposition Leader election from his couch in Queens, NY.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: The Fugitive is Official, Budget Bonanza Continues, and Mia Mottley Goes for the Three-Peat</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Azruddin Mohamed is now officially Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Opposition Leader despite US indictments. Meanwhile, Budget 2026 promises keep rolling out and Barbados prepares for another Mottley landslide.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Chinese Restaurant Adventure</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-speedeet-wilar-chinese-restaurant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-speedeet-wilar-chinese-restaurant/</guid><description>When Wilar&amp;rsquo;s uncle knows the owner of a Chinese restaurant near Kitty Cinema, the boys get a behind-the-scenes tour that changes everything Speedeet thought he knew about fried rice.</description></item><item><title>The Guyana Daily Brief - Tuesday, January 27, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath: $1.588 trillion in promises, 15,000 house lots, a school for autistic children, and the opposition still can&amp;rsquo;t find the door to the National Assembly.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: DIS IS HOW YOU BUILD A NATION! Budget 2026 is HISTORIC!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates Budget 2026 from Queens — praising the historic investments in housing, tourism, autism education, and agricultural development while wondering why opposition can&amp;rsquo;t find anything positive to say.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Elections Feb 11, US Visa Crackdowns, Trinidad's AI Push, and Jamaica's IMF Return</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Regional roundup: Mia Mottley goes for third term, US tightens visa rules for pregnant travelers, Trinidad partners with Microsoft on AI, and Jamaica seeks IMF help again.</description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Budget Day Showdown, Opposition's 'Fugitive' Gets His Day, and Berbice Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-monday-brief/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the Super Bowl of Guyanese politics: Budget 2026 drops while the opposition elects an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive&amp;rsquo; as their leader. Plus hotels, stadiums, and that $100,000 cash grant everyone&amp;rsquo;s been waiting for.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: BUDGET 2026 IS HERE! $100,000 For EVERYBODY While Opposition Busy Electing Fugitives!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates Budget 2026 and the $100,000 cash grant while questioning why the opposition is electing a man facing US extradition charges.</description></item><item><title>Saturday Brief: D-Day for Opposition Leader Vote Tomorrow</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Parliament meets Monday to elect Opposition Leader as rights groups sound alarm, plus chikungunya alert, Women&amp;#39;s Chamber tackles care work, and more from Guyana&amp;#39;s newspapers</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Why All Dis Noise About One Simple Vote?</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-25-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens responds to the Saturday Brief with his pro-government perspective on the Opposition Leader drama and Guyana&amp;#39;s progress</description></item><item><title>🎯 Bounty Board: Community Notices - January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-bounty-board/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-bounty-board/</guid><description>Community notices, events, and announcements from across Guyana. Jobs, events, lost &amp;amp; found, and more!</description></item><item><title>🔥 Bam-Bam Sally's Rumor Mill: January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-rumor-mill/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-rumor-mill/</guid><description>De hottest fictional gossip from de streets! All names fake, all scenarios made up, all entertainment guaranteed!</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>US-Caribbean visa tensions, Jamaica&amp;#39;s IMF loan, Trinidad-US partnership, Venezuela oil law changes, and regional cricket updates</description></item><item><title>The Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader drama continues, Budget 2026 incoming, Barama drops $1 billion, and INTERPOL busts gold smuggling ring</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Response: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>A diaspora perspective from Queens, NY — celebrating Budget 2026, Barama&amp;#39;s billion-dollar investment, and decisive government action</description></item><item><title>📸 Back-a-Truck: Weekend Deals - January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-back-a-truck/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-back-a-truck/</guid><description>Yuh weekend guide to de best deals in de markets! From Stabroek to Bourda, we got de prices and de vibes!</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Feb 11, Trinidad PM Kamla Navigates CARICOM, Caribbean Airlines Restructures</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>PM Mottley calls snap election for February 11 seeking historic third term, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s Kamla Persad-Bissessar defends CARICOM stance, and Caribbean Airlines closes its Barbados hub.</description></item><item><title>DJ Roadblock: Weekend Traffic Report &amp; Road Vibes</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-dj-roadblock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-dj-roadblock/</guid><description>DJ Roadblock brings you the Friday evening traffic situation and weekend road conditions across Guyana.</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: US Ambassador Says Nadir Can Have His Opinion, APAD Warns Against Fugitive Opposition Leader, Tourism Minister Takes River Cruise</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</guid><description>US Ambassador Theriot diplomatically sidesteps the Speaker drama, APAD joins the chorus against electing Mohamed, Minister Rodrigues cruises the Demerara, and over 200 Guyanese now certified in fibre optics. Plus opposition visits Tabatinga school and finds four workers.</description></item><item><title>Patriots Portfolio: This Week's Investment Opportunities for True Guyanese</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>Your weekly satirical investment advice from the most patriotic portfolio manager in Guyana.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Ambassador Theriot GETS IT, APAD Speaking FACTS, and River Cruises? This is PROGRESS!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens applauds Ambassador Theriot&amp;rsquo;s diplomatic wisdom, celebrates APAD for putting country over politics, and explains why river cruises prove Guyana is becoming a REAL tourism destination.</description></item><item><title>Bam-Bam Sally's Rumor Mill: The Opposition Leader Tea Is SCALDING This Week</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-rumor-mill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-rumor-mill/</guid><description>The completely fictional whispers making rounds in Georgetown this week. All names changed, all situations imagined, all entertainment guaranteed.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Goes to Polls Feb 11, Trinidad's PM Kamla Warns About 'Divisiveness', Jamaica Gets $415M Hurricane Relief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley calls Barbados elections for February 11, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s new PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar navigates US-Venezuela tensions, Jamaica secures IMF emergency funding for Hurricane Melissa recovery, and Caribbean Airlines restructures its regional operations.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: Linden-Mabura Road at 62%, Gas-to-Energy Deadlines Extended, Bayrock Stadium Opens Jan 31</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-progress-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-progress-report/</guid><description>Tracking what the government promised vs what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening. This week: Linden-Mabura road hits 62%, gas plant deadlines pushed back (again), and Linden finally getting its stadium.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Speaker Nadir Speaking FACTS, Opposition Should Thank Him for the Warning</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens applauds Speaker Nadir for telling the truth about the Opposition Leader situation, explains why the Belgian port deal proves Guyana is the Caribbean&amp;rsquo;s rising star, and questions why Charrandass is making TikToks instead of reading laws.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: Speaker Nadir Says Electing 'International Fugitive' Would Stain Parliament, 70kg Cocaine Bust, Belgium Wants to Build Our Ports</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Speaker Nadir drops the &amp;lsquo;international fugitive&amp;rsquo; bomb on WIN, 70kg of cocaine found in Parika, Belgium wants to help build our ports, IATA talks airport improvements, and AG Nandlall schools Charrandass on what &amp;lsquo;fugitive offender&amp;rsquo; actually means.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — January 21, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures US$6.7 billion for Hurricane Melissa recovery, Maduro claims presidency from Brooklyn jail, Haiti TPS termination hearing continues, and Trinidad welcomes new PM Stuart Young.</description></item><item><title>Progress Report: Government Promises vs Reality Check - January 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-progress-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-progress-report/</guid><description>Tracking what the government promised vs what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening. This week: Solar farms on track, garbage collection off track, and the eternal question of when that overpass is coming.</description></item><item><title>The Rumor Mill: What Georgetown Whispering This Week</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-rumor-mill/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-rumor-mill/</guid><description>The completely fictional whispers making rounds in Georgetown this week. All names changed, all situations imagined, all entertainment guaranteed.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Opposition Leader Coming Monday, Police Academy Scandal, and Georgetown Is STILL a Dumpster Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader election finally set for Monday, Police Academy sexual exploitation scandal rocks the force, and Georgetown garbage crisis deepens as Mayor backs out of meeting.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: 'Finally Somebody Standing Up for Democracy!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates the Opposition Leader election announcement, defends Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s garbage situation, and explains why solar power proves the PPP is the best thing since sliced bread.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Progress Despite the Noise</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens explains why the Opposition Leader delay is actually democracy at work, the Police Academy scandal is opposition propaganda, and Georgetown garbage is a City Hall problem.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: Opposition Leader Monday Showdown, Solar Power for Linden, and Georgetown's Garbage Emergency</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Speaker Nadir finally schedules Opposition Leader vote for Monday while calling candidate an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive.&amp;rsquo; Plus: Linden gets solar farms, Georgetown drowning in garbage, and the Mohameds saga continues. Your 5-minute news circus.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – January 20, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute tour of regional chaos, served with rum punch&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-the-maduro-situation-still-situating">🇻🇪 THE MADURO SITUATION: STILL SITUATING&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two weeks after Uncle Sam yoinked Nicolás Maduro out of Caracas like a bad tooth, the Caribbean is still dealing with the hangover. Thousands of tourists got stranded. Cruise ships played musical chairs in Barbados harbour. And Trinidad? Well, T&amp;amp;T said &amp;ldquo;sure ting&amp;rdquo; to letting U.S. military use their airports, which Venezuela called a betrayal. PM Kamla then spent the weekend cussing out the Energy Chamber for allegedly caring more about foreign oil companies than local contractors. Classic Trini Monday.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Hospital Cat Hunt</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Speedeet brother Derek get bite by carpet labaria at Tumatumari and end up in Georgetown Hospital. But while de family visiting, Speedeet and Wilar find a different kind of adventure in de hospital compound.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday Brief: Cash Grants Are So Last Year, Georgetown Is a Dumpster Fire, and Teachers Want Answers</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute Guyanese news circus — now with 100% less cash grants&lt;/em> ☕🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-cash-grants-not-sustainable--president">💸 CASH GRANTS: &amp;ldquo;NOT SUSTAINABLE&amp;rdquo; — PRESIDENT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What Happened:&lt;/strong> President Ali declared that future cash grants are &amp;ldquo;not sustainable,&amp;rdquo; warning that &amp;ldquo;some people would use this as a political opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Backstory:&lt;/strong> Just one year ago, the government was &amp;ldquo;committed to making future cash grants.&amp;rdquo; What a difference 365 days makes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Math:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2025: &amp;ldquo;We are committed to future cash grants!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2026: &amp;ldquo;Cash grants are not sustainable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Also 2026: Oil production approaching 1 million barrels per day.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dem Boys Seh:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;When election coming, cash grant sustainable. When election done, cash grant unsustainable. Is like magic — de money just disappear!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Sustainable Governance, Not Reckless Giveaways</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>From Queens, New York — Where we understand fiscal responsibility&lt;/em> 🇬🇾🗽&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="greetings-from-the-diaspora">Greetings from the Diaspora!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ah, another day, another set of headlines from Guyana that the critics want to twist into something negative. But Uncle Ramesh here to set the record straight for all my fellow Guyanese overseas who want to understand what&amp;rsquo;s REALLY happening in we homeland.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-on-cash-grants-responsible-leadership">💰 ON CASH GRANTS: RESPONSIBLE LEADERSHIP&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So the President said cash grants are &amp;ldquo;not sustainable,&amp;rdquo; and suddenly everybody vex? Let me ask you something: which responsible government just keeps handing out money without a plan?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Former Finance Minister Admits Exxon Exploited Us, Venezuela Border Watch, and Pay-To-Party Culture</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</guid><description>Winston Jordan finally admits what everyone knew, PM Phillips says troops are ready for anything Venezuelan, and birthday parties now cost admission.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh Responds: Jordan Finally Talking Truth, Border Security Strong, and Mash Coming!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh sets the record straight on who really signed that oil contract, praises border vigilance, and gets ready for Republic Day.</description></item><item><title>🎯 Uncle Ramesh's Bounty Board - January 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-bounty-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-bounty-board/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh offering rewards fuh solving de nation&amp;#39;s greatest mysteries. Terms and Whose Friend Yuh Is may apply.</description></item><item><title>📢 Bam-Bam Sally's This Week in Rumors</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-bam-bam-sally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-bam-bam-sally/</guid><description>If yuh ain&amp;#39;t hear it from me, it ain&amp;#39;t worth hearing! Bam-Bam Sally got de HOT tea dis week!</description></item><item><title>🚗 DJ Roadblock Traffic Report: January 19, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-dj-roadblock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-dj-roadblock/</guid><description>Yuh weekly guide to navigating de madness on Guyana roads. West Ruimveldt crying, Regent Street swimming, and de cones multiplying!</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Oil Talk, Border Soldiers, and Birthday Party Entry Fees</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar from Pike Street, Kitty try to understand oil contracts, wonder why soldiers watching de border, and complain about paying to attend birthday parties.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Solar Panel Mix-Up</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Speedeet cousin from Rupununi come to visit and bring story about the government solar panels. But Wilar grandmother got she own ideas about &amp;#39;free electricity.&amp;#39;</description></item><item><title>📸 Back-a-Truck: This Week's Wildest Sightings</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-back-a-truck/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-back-a-truck/</guid><description>You can&amp;#39;t make dis up! The most absurd, hilarious, and head-scratching sightings from around Guyana this week.</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Hotels, Digital Records, and Why Adults Confusing</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar from Pike Street, Kitty break down fancy hotels, digital health records, and why de women cricket team is de real MVP.</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar and the Mystery of the Missing Medical Records</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>When Speedeet&amp;rsquo;s grandmother can&amp;rsquo;t find her medical file at the clinic, the two friends discover that going digital isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as pressing a button.</description></item><item><title>Sunday's Guyana Brief - Hotels Multiply, Health Goes Digital, and Cricket Women Keep Winning</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Another US$18M hotel opens, your medical records go online, President Ali says cash grants aren&amp;rsquo;t sustainable (after promising one), Women&amp;rsquo;s cricket squad stays undefeated, and Fruta Conquerors lose their president after 11 months.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Hotels Mean JOBS, Women Cricketers Making Us PROUD, and Stop Complaining!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Women&amp;rsquo;s T20 squad, defends the hotel boom, explains why digital health records are PROGRESS, and asks why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t just be happy for once.</description></item><item><title>🎯 Uncle Ramesh's Bounty Board - January 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-bounty-board/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-bounty-board/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh offering rewards fuh solving de nation&amp;#39;s greatest mysteries. Terms and Whose Friend Yuh Is may apply.</description></item><item><title>🏆 Patriots Portfolio - Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh&amp;rsquo;s Weekly Celebration of Guyanese Excellence&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-this-weeks-patriot-dr-goldenheart-perseverance">🌟 This Week&amp;rsquo;s Patriot: Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Healer Who Never Bills Twice&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="the-legend">The Legend&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Every week, Uncle Ramesh searches high and low for Guyanese who exemplify the True Patriot Spirit™ - that special combination of unwavering government support, photogenic community service, and the ability to appear at ribbon-cutting ceremonies on short notice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week, we celebrate &lt;strong>Dr. Goldenheart Perseverance&lt;/strong>, a physician whose dedication to healing is matched only by her dedication to praising every new government health initiative, regardless of whether the clinic has running water.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Saturday's Guyana Brief: Toy Guns Guarding Your Groceries, Solar Power Rising, and Guyana Women Battle Jamaica Tonight!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Security guards caught with toy guns at supermarkets, US$8.14M solar farm lights up Charity, GBTI launches private banking for the rich, and Guyana Women seek redemption against Jamaica under the lights!</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Solar Success, Security Solutions, and Stop Crying Over Cricket!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh responds to the Daily Brief&amp;rsquo;s negativity with FACTS about solar investment, the government&amp;rsquo;s swift response to security issues, and a reminder that our women cricketers are STILL defending champions!</description></item><item><title>📸 Back-a-Truck: Wha We Spot Dis Week</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-back-a-truck/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-17-back-a-truck/</guid><description>Absurd tings spotted around Guyana dis week. You can&amp;#39;t make dis up!</description></item><item><title>Dr. Sharmila Persaud: From Berbice to Brain Surgery</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>A Weekly Profile of Guyanese Excellence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore, Dr. Sharmila Persaud is performing some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most complex brain surgeries. But every morning, she looks at a photo on her desk: her grandmother&amp;rsquo;s wooden house in Berbice, where she grew up without electricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-journey">The Journey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;People ask me how I got from there to here,&amp;rdquo; Dr. Persaud says, gesturing around her state-of-the-art operating suite. &amp;ldquo;I tell them: I got here because I started there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The New Georgetown: How Guyana's Capital is Transforming</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-guyanese-horizon-georgetown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-guyanese-horizon-georgetown/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>A Monthly Feature Celebrating Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Progress&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Walk down Main Street today, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see something remarkable happening. Georgetown, once known for its colonial charm mixed with urban challenges, is undergoing a transformation that would have seemed impossible just five years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-numbers-tell-the-story">The Numbers Tell the Story&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since 2020, Georgetown has seen:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>40+ new businesses&lt;/strong> opening on Main Street alone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>$500 million invested&lt;/strong> in waterfront development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>300% increase&lt;/strong> in tourism infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>12 new hotels&lt;/strong> under construction or recently opened&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="beyond-the-statistics">Beyond the Statistics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>But the real story isn&amp;rsquo;t in the numbers—it&amp;rsquo;s in the people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Why All This Oil Drama Is Just Opposition Noise</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="-uncle-rameshs-take-">🇬🇾 UNCLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S TAKE 🇬🇾&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Straight Talk from Queens to Georgetown&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Greetings from New York, where is cold but not as cold as some people hearts when it come to seeing Guyana succeed! 🌎&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawd, ayuh hear de noise today? Kaieteur News writing like we oil done finish and Parliament is some kind of dictatorship. Let Uncle Ramesh give ayuh de REAL story, not this opposition propaganda.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-the-oil-crisis-that-isnt">🛢️ THE OIL &amp;ldquo;CRISIS&amp;rdquo; THAT ISN&amp;rsquo;T&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>De Headline:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Oil wells running dry! Disaster!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&lt;strong>De Reality:&lt;/strong> We producing MORE oil than ever and making BILLIONS!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief - Oil Wells Racing to Empty, Speaker Races to India</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-friday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Guyana! ☕&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Friday, where our oil fields are being liquidated faster than a closing-down sale, our Speaker fled to India while Parliament remains closed, and Exxon&amp;rsquo;s 75% &amp;ldquo;expense deduction&amp;rdquo; makes Nigerian email scams look amateur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Today&amp;rsquo;s menu:&lt;/strong> The Great Oil Heist exposed (75% goes to &amp;ldquo;costs&amp;rdquo;), Speaker escapes to India during constitutional crisis, French Ambassador politely suggests democracy might be nice, Mashramani launches because at least we can party, and President Ali promises no Venezuela deals (this time he means it, promise).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: De Report-A-Hole FACTS (With Receipts!)</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-uncle-ramesh-daily-laugh-response/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-uncle-ramesh-daily-laugh-response/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh brings DATA, CHARTS, and REALITY to the pothole app debate. Comedy Crew about to get fact-checked!</description></item><item><title>Daily Laugh: De Report-A-Hole Disaster</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-daily-laugh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-daily-laugh/</guid><description>Government launches pothole app. Uncle Ramesh becomes their #1 user. Chaos ensues. Yellow paint involved.</description></item><item><title>DJ Roadblock Traffic Report: January 16, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-dj-roadblock-traffic-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-dj-roadblock-traffic-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>🎙️ WAAAAAH GWAAN GEORGETOWN! Is ya boy DJ Roadblock comin&amp;rsquo; at you LIVE from de dashboard of me lil Raum, stuck behind a minibus dat ain&amp;rsquo;t move in 20 minutes!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-this-weeks-road-disasters">🚗 This Week&amp;rsquo;s Road Disasters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sheriff Street Crater Update:&lt;/strong> Dat pothole by de KFC? She get BIGGER, family. Man tell me he see a Fielder go down in deh last Tuesday and ain&amp;rsquo;t come back out yet. If you driving Sheriff Street, say a prayer and hug de left side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>📈 Weekly Progress Report: January 8-15, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-progress-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-progress-report/</guid><description>A factual summary of PPP/C government accomplishments for the week of January 8-15, 2026. No commentary, just documented achievements and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>🔍 [CRITICAL] Wednesday Brief: Guyanese Takes IICA Helm, Census Controversy, and Cybercrime Crackdown</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Muhammad Ibrahim becomes IICA Director-General, census data sparks housing debate, cybercrime law faces criticism, and AG slams courts for ignoring legislation.</description></item><item><title>😊 [PRO-GOV] Uncle Ramesh: When De Government Does De Math Right (For Once)</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh does the math on the census data and discovers the government was actually planning ahead. Who knew? Plus, finally some people heading to jail.</description></item><item><title>Bam-Bam Sally's This Week in Rumors</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-rumor-mill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-rumor-mill/</guid><description>Eh-eh! Leh we see wha whispers floatin&amp;#39; &amp;#39;round Guyana dis week. Now wid ratings so yuh know how serious de talk really is!</description></item><item><title>De Boys Seh: Wha Speedeet &amp; Wilar Talking About Dis Week</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-de-boys-seh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-de-boys-seh/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar share dem thoughts on cricket, video games, school lunch, and why adults always saying &amp;lsquo;back in me days.&amp;rsquo; Short takes from two 12-year-olds!</description></item><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: De Mango Tree Incident</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-speedeet-wilar-mango-tree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-speedeet-wilar-mango-tree/</guid><description>Speedeet got a plan fuh get de biggest mango from Mr. Chan shop yard, and Wilar know is trouble but he going anyway. Wha could go wrong?</description></item><item><title>Tuesday's Guyana Brief: Apps, Laws, and Courtroom Drama</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-14-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-14-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>Attorney General scolds magistrates for ignoring laws, government promises 87 new apps, and President Ali discovers swamps can become highways (who knew?). Welcome to Tuesday in paradise!</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: The Brief Jokes About Laws While Missing the Point Entirely!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-14-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-14-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh sets the record straight on judicial reforms, explains why apps ARE revolutionary, and defends the gas-to-energy project the Brief clearly doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand.</description></item><item><title>🔍 [CRITICAL] Monday Brief: Crime Stats, Search &amp; Rescue Upgrade, and Traffic Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-monday-brief/</guid><description>Murders up 11% despite overall crime drop, new $123M search and rescue system launched, over 3,100 traffic offences in one week, and financial system reforms promised.</description></item><item><title>😊 [PRO-GOV] Uncle Ramesh: When De Numbers Tell De REAL Story</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh explains why 25% crime reduction is actually amazing, and why spending $123M on safety makes sense. Progress is progress!</description></item><item><title>Tuesday's Guyana Brief - Census Drops After 4 Years, Democracy Still Missing</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Guyana! ☕&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Tuesday, where census data finally arrives (only 4 years late!) and Parliament continues its record-breaking streak of doing absolutely nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Today&amp;rsquo;s menu:&lt;/strong> Census numbers drop after a 4-year delay, oil wells still racing toward empty, Parliament enters Week 11 of ghosting us, and unauthorized supermarkets get shut down faster than you can say &amp;ldquo;planning permission.&amp;rdquo; Also, Guyana can&amp;rsquo;t say no to the US. Shocking, we know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Census Critics Don't Understand How Government Works</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-tuesday-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-13-tuesday-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="uncle-rameshs-take">Uncle Ramesh&amp;rsquo;s Take&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Straight Talk from Brooklyn to Georgetown&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Listen, I&amp;rsquo;m reading all these opposition newspapers complaining about the census taking 4 years. You know what? They don&amp;rsquo;t understand how real governance works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me break it down for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-census-took-4-years-thats-called-being-thorough">📊 CENSUS TOOK 4 YEARS? THAT&amp;rsquo;S CALLED BEING THOROUGH!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All these critics crying &amp;ldquo;4 years is too long!&amp;rdquo; You know what I say? &lt;strong>Quality over speed!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="background-color: #E8F5E9; padding: 15px; border-left: 4px solid #4CAF50; margin: 20px 0;">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>878,674 people on census day 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>956,044 projected by end 2024&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monday's Guyana Brief: The Week Starts With a Yelling</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-12-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-12-monday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Guyana! ☕&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Monday, where last week&amp;rsquo;s problems are this week&amp;rsquo;s problems with a fresh coat of optimistic denial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing got fixed over the weekend. Shocked? You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Today&amp;rsquo;s menu:&lt;/strong> GuySuCo gets scolded (again), The Mohameds perfect the art of not leaving, crime stats achieve Olympic-level creativity, and we learn why complaining about bribery is somehow worse than actual bribery. Just another week in paradise!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="x1f4ca-todays-numbers">📊 TODAY&amp;rsquo;S NUMBERS&lt;/h2>
&lt;div style="background-color: #E8F5E9; padding: 15px; border-left: 4px solid #4CAF50; margin: 20px 0;">
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mohamed Appeals:&lt;/strong> 47 (their lawyer&amp;rsquo;s yacht fund thanks you)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take on Today's News: Finally, Some Good News for a Change!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-12-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-12-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="x1f1ecx1f1fe-uncle-rameshs-take-x1f1ecx1f1fe">🇬🇾 UNCLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S TAKE 🇬🇾&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Your Uncle from the Diaspora Who Actually Reads Past the Headlines&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Greetings from Toronto, where it cold like ice but me heart warm with pride! ☕&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ayuh know Uncle Ramesh don&amp;rsquo;t like to complain. Me sit down every morning with me tea, reading all four newspapers, and today me had to say – why everybody so negative? The government doing WORK! But all some people want to do is find fault. Well, not today. Today, Uncle Ramesh going set the record straight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: The Brief Writes a Whole Article and STILL Misses The Point!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-11-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-11-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cle-rameshs-hot-take">CLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S HOT TAKE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sunday, January 11, 2026&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>[Uncle Ramesh on his verandah, Sunday paper in hand, reading The Brief&amp;rsquo;s Sunday edition, shaking his head so hard the neighbors looking]&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Listen nah, it&amp;rsquo;s SUNDAY! Day of REST! Day of PEACE!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this youngin&amp;rsquo; at The Brief write the LONGEST article yet and STILL managing to miss every single point!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let Uncle Ramesh break down where The Brief went wrong (AGAIN).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunday's Guyana Brief: The Mohameds Strike Back</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-11-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-11-sunday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: center; padding: 40px 30px; background: linear-gradient(135deg, #009E60 0%, #FCD116 50%, #CE1126 100%); border-radius: 15px; margin-bottom: 30px;">
&lt;h1 style="color: white; font-size: 36px; margin: 0 0 15px 0; text-shadow: 2px 2px 4px rgba(0,0,0,0.3);">&amp;#x1F1EC;&amp;#x1F1FE; THE GUYANA BRIEF &amp;#x1F1EC;&amp;#x1F1FE;&lt;/h1>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 18px; margin: 0; font-weight: 500;">Your 5-Minute Sunday News Circus&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 14px; margin: 10px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.9;">Sunday, January 12, 2026&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 12px; margin: 5px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.8; font-style: italic;">Sponsored by: Lawyers Who Bill By The Appeal&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: The Brief Discovers Math But Still Can't Add!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-10-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-10-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cle-rameshs-hot-take">CLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S HOT TAKE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Saturday, January 10, 2026&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>[Uncle Ramesh reading Saturday&amp;rsquo;s Brief, calculator in hand, shaking his head at the math]&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Listen nah, The Brief discovered MATH this weekend! They calculating 69,000 volts! They counting houses per day! They adding up murder rates!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Problem is: They still getting the CONCLUSIONS wrong!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let Uncle Ramesh show this youngin&amp;rsquo; how numbers ACTUALLY work.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="âš-69000-volts-the-brief-finally-got-one-right">âš¡ 69,000 VOLTS: THE BRIEF FINALLY GOT ONE RIGHT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Brief says: &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Contractor almost killed himself&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Saturday's Guyana Brief: Weekend News Circus</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-10-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-10-saturday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: center; padding: 40px 30px; background: linear-gradient(135deg, #009E60 0%, #FCD116 50%, #CE1126 100%); border-radius: 15px; margin-bottom: 30px;">
&lt;h1 style="color: white; font-size: 36px; margin: 0 0 15px 0; text-shadow: 2px 2px 4px rgba(0,0,0,0.3);">E GUYANA BRIEF 1>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 18px; margin: 0; font-weight: 500;">Your 5-Minute Weekend News Circus&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 14px; margin: 10px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.9;">Saturday, January 10, 2026&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 12px; margin: 5px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.8; font-style: italic;">Sponsored by: Contractors Who Can't See 69,000-Volt Lines&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: So NOW The Brief Worries About Deportations? Where Was You Before?</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-09-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-09-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cle-rameshs-hot-take">CLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S HOT TAKE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Friday, January 9, 2026&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>[Uncle Ramesh sipping his Friday coffee, reading The Brief&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Storage Unit&amp;rdquo; headline, choking on his coffee]&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>STORAGE UNIT?! &lt;strong>STORAGE UNIT?!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This youngin&amp;rsquo; really called Guyana &amp;ldquo;America&amp;rsquo;s Storage Unit&amp;rdquo; and think he CLEVER?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let Uncle Ramesh break down why The Brief got it HALF right and HALF wrong (as usual).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="ge-unit---cute-headline-wrong-take">GE UNIT&amp;quot; - CUTE HEADLINE, WRONG TAKE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Brief says: &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Guyana volunteers as America&amp;rsquo;s storage unit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief: Storage Unit Edition</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-09-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-09-friday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: center; padding: 40px 30px; background: linear-gradient(135deg, #009E60 0%, #FCD116 50%, #CE1126 100%); border-radius: 15px; margin-bottom: 30px;">
&lt;h1 style="color: white; font-size: 36px; margin: 0 0 15px 0; text-shadow: 2px 2px 4px rgba(0,0,0,0.3);">E GUYANA BRIEF 1>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 18px; margin: 0; font-weight: 500;">Your 5-Minute Guyana News Digest&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 14px; margin: 10px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.9;">Friday, January 9, 2026&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 12px; margin: 5px 0 0 0; opacity: 0.8; font-style: italic;">Sponsored by: Bridge Repair Funds (Just Kidding, Those Don't Exist)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: This Youngin' Thinks Trump's a Hero? PLEASE!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-08-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-08-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cle-rameshs-hot-take">CLE RAMESH&amp;rsquo;S HOT TAKE&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Thursday, January 8, 2026&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>[Uncle Ramesh reading THE GUYANA BRIEF on his iPad, coffee in hand, shaking his head so hard his reading glasses almost fall off]&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Listen nah, I just read this youngin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Guyana Brief&amp;rdquo; and my blood pressure went UP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This child writing like Trump is some kinda superhero! &amp;ldquo;Uber-kidnapped a president!&amp;rdquo; Like is a GOOD thing?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let Uncle Ramesh school you on what REALLY happening here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>THE GUYANA BRIEF: Thursday's Guyana News Circus</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-08-thursday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:47:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-08-thursday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: center; padding: 20px; background: linear-gradient(135deg, #009E60 0%, #FCD116 50%, #CE1126 100%); border-radius: 10px; margin-bottom: 30px;">
&lt;h1 style="color: white; font-size: 36px; margin: 0;">E GUYANA BRIEF 1>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 18px; margin: 10px 0 0 0;">&lt;strong>Your 5-Minute Guyana News Digest&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p style="color: white; font-size: 14px; margin: 5px 0 0 0; font-style: italic;">Sponsored by: Strong Coffee &amp; Questionable Life Choices&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="ng-maduro-gets-the-ultimate-surprise-party">NG: MADURO GETS THE ULTIMATE SURPRISE PARTY&lt;/h2>
&lt;div style="background: #fff3cd; border-left: 5px solid #ffc107; padding: 15px; margin: 20px 0; border-radius: 5px;">
&lt;strong>STATS:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Operation Speed: Faster than DoorDash&lt;br>
Caribbean Group Chat Status: Wild&lt;br>
Guyana's Official Response: Diplomatically Thrilled
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Y&amp;rsquo;all, the Americans just Uber-kidnapped an entire president. Not even DoorDash is that efficient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Funny Take on Guyana Daily News!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="welcome-">Welcome! ‚&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Your daily dose of Guyanese news with comedy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="youtube-scripts---january-27-2026">YOUTUBE SCRIPTS - January 27, 2026&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="budget-2026-aftermath">Budget 2026 Aftermath&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>================================================================================&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="script-1-60-second-version-youtube-shorts--tiktok--reels">SCRIPT 1: 60-SECOND VERSION (YouTube Shorts / TikTok / Reels)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>================================================================================&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title:&lt;/strong> &amp;ldquo;Budget 2026: $1.588 TRILLION! What You Need to Know | Guyana News&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Description:&lt;/strong>
Budget 2026 just dropped! $1.588 trillion in spending, 15,000 house lots, Guyana&amp;rsquo;s FIRST autism school, and record tourism numbers. Here&amp;rsquo;s your 60-second breakdown! 🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;p>#GuyanaNews #Budget2026 #Guyana #Caribbean&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SCRIPT:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s up Guyana? Budget 2026 just dropped and the numbers are MASSIVE!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-24/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="caribbean-daily-brief">Caribbean Daily Brief&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="saturday-january-24-2026">Saturday, January 24, 2026&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Your regional roundup from across the Caribbean&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="-good-morning-caribbean">🌴 GOOD MORNING, CARIBBEAN!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>From Bridgetown to Kingston, Port of Spain to Georgetown — here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s making waves across the region today!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="-us-caribbean-relations-the-tension-continues">🇺🇸 US-CARIBBEAN RELATIONS: THE TENSION CONTINUES&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Headlines:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IMF approves $415M emergency assistance for Jamaica&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caribbean nations facing stricter US visa scrutiny in 2026&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Barbados FM concerned about US military strikes bypassing &amp;ldquo;due process&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>US reaffirms partnership with Trinidad &amp;amp; Tobago&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Brief:&lt;/strong>
The US and Caribbean relationship looking more complicated than a Port of Spain traffic roundabout!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/daily-brief-2026-01-24/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-daily-brief">The Daily Brief&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="saturday-january-24-2026">Saturday, January 24, 2026&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Your satirical summary of Guyana&amp;rsquo;s news — Read all four papers in 5-6 minutes so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="-opposition-leader-drama-the-longest-election-ever">🏛️ OPPOSITION LEADER DRAMA: THE LONGEST ELECTION EVER&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Headlines:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>APNU says they&amp;rsquo;ll likely abstain from Opposition Leader vote&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mohamed says he&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;scared&amp;rdquo; ahead of Monday&amp;rsquo;s vote&lt;/li>
&lt;li>APNU warns cut borrowing for Budget 2026 as oil prices slide&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Brief:&lt;/strong>
So Monday&amp;rsquo;s the big day, right? Wrong. We&amp;rsquo;ve been saying &amp;ldquo;Monday&amp;rsquo;s the big day&amp;rdquo; since September. Azruddin Mohamed, the US-indicted gold dealer who somehow controls a quarter of the National Assembly, is apparently &amp;ldquo;scared&amp;rdquo; about the Opposition Leader vote. Scared of what? Losing? Winning? Having to explain to his American lawyers why he&amp;rsquo;s running a country instead of running from an extradition warrant?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-24/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="uncle-rameshs-response">Uncle Ramesh&amp;rsquo;s Response&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="saturday-january-24-2026">Saturday, January 24, 2026&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A diaspora perspective from Queens, NY&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="from-queens-with-pride-">FROM QUEENS WITH PRIDE 🇬🇾&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Good morning from Richmond Hill! Waking up this Saturday to some EXCELLENT news from back home, and I just have to share with my fellow patriotic Guyanese in the diaspora!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="-budget-2026-another-historic-moment-coming">💰 BUDGET 2026: ANOTHER HISTORIC MOMENT COMING!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While some negative people complaining about Budget 2026, I watching from here and seeing PROGRESS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/youtube-scripts-2026-01-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/youtube-scripts-2026-01-24/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="youtube-scripts-for-january-24-2026">YouTube Scripts for January 24, 2026&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-guyana-brief--daily-news-roundup">The Guyana Brief — Daily News Roundup&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="script-1-60-second-version-youtube-shorts--tiktok">SCRIPT 1: 60-SECOND VERSION (YouTube Shorts / TikTok)&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>[TITLE CARD: THE GUYANA BRIEF — Jan 24, 2026]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>[AVATAR ON SCREEN]&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Wha gwan everybody! Here&amp;rsquo;s your 60-second Guyana news roundup!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Budget 2026 dropping Monday! You KNOW Finance Minister gon say &amp;rsquo;largest budget in history.&amp;rsquo; They say that every year. At this point, it&amp;rsquo;s not news, it&amp;rsquo;s tradition!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[Quick transition]&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>