<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Regional on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/regional/</link><description>Recent content in Regional on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/regional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Carnival Tuesday Approaches, Barbados Cabinet Sworn In, and Maduro Pleads Not Guilty in New York</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-16-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-16-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Caribbean! 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carnival Tuesday is tomorrow in Trinidad, Barbados has a brand new cabinet, Maduro pleaded not guilty in New York, and the US is making it harder for Caribbean nationals to visit. Your Monday regional roundup.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-trinidad-jouvert-done-parade-of-the-bands-tomorrow">🎭 Trinidad: J&amp;rsquo;ouvert Done, Parade of the Bands Tomorrow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Carnival Monday is winding down in Trinidad after a J&amp;rsquo;ouvert that started before dawn and a full day of revelry through Port of Spain, Tunapuna, and beyond. Police confiscated an impressive collection of weapons during early morning exercises — because some people apparently think Carnival is a medieval tournament.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival Monday Madness, Barbados Swears In a Government, and Cuba Can't Catch a Break</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-15-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-15-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>Good morning, Caribbean! 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Carnival Monday in Trinidad, election aftermath in Barbados, and Cuba is still trying to keep the lights on. Your weekly regional roundup of who&amp;rsquo;s partying, who&amp;rsquo;s governing, and who&amp;rsquo;s wondering where the fuel went.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-trinidad-carnival-monday--jouvert-in-full-swing">🎭 Trinidad Carnival Monday — J&amp;rsquo;ouvert in Full Swing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Carnival Monday in Trinidad and the streets of Tunapuna are packed with revellers covered in paint, mud, and questionable life decisions. J&amp;rsquo;ouvert started before dawn and will not stop until Trinidad collectively decides it&amp;rsquo;s had enough — which historically takes about 48 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief – Friday, February 13, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-13-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-13-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley&amp;rsquo;s historic third sweep. Caribbean takes centre stage in Panama. US tightening visa screws on Caribbean nationals. Italy wins at cricket. And Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s energy billions.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Votes, Trinidad Talks Energy, Cuba Still Running On Fumes</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-12-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-12-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls in snap elections, Trinidad positions itself as energy gold standard, and Cuba&amp;#39;s fuel crisis means airlines can&amp;#39;t even refuel on the island.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — US Warships Still Blowing Up Boats, Barbados Heads to Polls, Jamaica Gets IMF Lifeline, and the Region Wonders What Happened to Sovereignty</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US military campaign in Caribbean waters has killed over 117 people, Barbados elections are 8 days away, Jamaica secured $415M in IMF emergency aid, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM praised the boat strikes, and CARICOM can&amp;rsquo;t agree on anything except that things are complicated.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your regional roundup from across the Caribbean&lt;/em> 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-jamaica-gets-us415-million-imf-emergency-loan">🇯🇲 Jamaica Gets US$415 Million IMF Emergency Loan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The IMF Executive Board has approved Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s request for emergency financial assistance of approximately &lt;strong>US$415 million&lt;/strong> to help meet urgent balance-of-payments needs. This comes as the region continues to navigate economic pressures from various global factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s Finance Minister is expected to outline how these funds will be deployed to stabilize the economy and protect vulnerable populations. The country has been a model for IMF structural adjustment programs in the past, but this emergency assistance signals ongoing challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — January 21, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures US$6.7 billion for Hurricane Melissa recovery, Maduro claims presidency from Brooklyn jail, Haiti TPS termination hearing continues, and Trinidad welcomes new PM Stuart Young.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – January 20, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute tour of regional chaos, served with rum punch&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-the-maduro-situation-still-situating">🇻🇪 THE MADURO SITUATION: STILL SITUATING&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two weeks after Uncle Sam yoinked Nicolás Maduro out of Caracas like a bad tooth, the Caribbean is still dealing with the hangover. Thousands of tourists got stranded. Cruise ships played musical chairs in Barbados harbour. And Trinidad? Well, T&amp;amp;T said &amp;ldquo;sure ting&amp;rdquo; to letting U.S. military use their airports, which Venezuela called a betrayal. PM Kamla then spent the weekend cussing out the Energy Chamber for allegedly caring more about foreign oil companies than local contractors. Classic Trini Monday.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>