<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Housing on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/housing/</link><description>Recent content in Housing on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/housing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Mortgages, Nurses, and the Brief's Selective Memory</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh is a retired accountant from Berbice, now living in Queens, New York. He reads the papers — especially the Chronicle — and provides his perspective.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Monday morning and the Brief leading with Azruddin showing up late. That&amp;rsquo;s the headline? A man who is US-indicted, facing extradition, and can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to arrive on time to his own hearing — and the Brief treating it like comedy instead of asking why the Opposition Leader has such contempt for the judicial process?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Got a Plan fuh Everything and All Dem Could Do is Complain!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition still complaining while the government delivering 53,000 house lots, 9 million carbon credits, and a five-year sugar plan. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, Lady Jags scoring 14 goals, and Minister Browne put Dawn Hastings in she place.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: 'Budget 2026 Is What Development Looks Like — Take Notes!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the papers independently and finds plenty to celebrate: Budget 2026&amp;rsquo;s massive investments, a fancy new Georgetown hotel, record tourism numbers, and the UK rolling out the red carpet for Guyana. The opposition? Still complaining.</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: GRA Officers Fired Over Mohamed Vehicle Transfers, RUSAL Returns, and Christopher Ram Prescribes Fiscal Ozempic</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-friday-brief/</guid><description>GRA employees terminated for helping sanctioned businessman move vehicles, Russian aluminum company returns to Guyana, and Christopher Ram says the government needs appetite control for spending.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: GRA Doing Its Job, RUSAL Means JOBS, and Christopher Ram Needs to Relax</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-30-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens explains why GRA firing corrupt officers is GOOD news, RUSAL returning means JOBS for Linden, and Christopher Ram should let the government cook.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: The Fugitive is Official, Budget Bonanza Continues, and Mia Mottley Goes for the Three-Peat</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Azruddin Mohamed is now officially Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Opposition Leader despite US indictments. Meanwhile, Budget 2026 promises keep rolling out and Barbados prepares for another Mottley landslide.</description></item><item><title>The Guyana Daily Brief - Tuesday, January 27, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath: $1.588 trillion in promises, 15,000 house lots, a school for autistic children, and the opposition still can&amp;rsquo;t find the door to the National Assembly.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: DIS IS HOW YOU BUILD A NATION! Budget 2026 is HISTORIC!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates Budget 2026 from Queens — praising the historic investments in housing, tourism, autism education, and agricultural development while wondering why opposition can&amp;rsquo;t find anything positive to say.</description></item></channel></rss>