<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Tourism on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tourism/</link><description>Recent content in Tourism on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tourism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: US Strikes Boats Near Venezuela, Jamaica Gets $415M Emergency IMF Loan, and T&amp;T Says Airspace is Fine</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US is blowing up boats in the Caribbean, Jamaica needs emergency cash after Hurricane Melissa, Trinidad says everything is normal (it&amp;#39;s not), and the T20 World Cup has kicked off.</description></item><item><title>Patriots Portfolio: Budget 2026 Deep Dive — Where Is the $1.588 Trillion Actually Going?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-06-patriots-portfolio/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Patriots Portfolio breaks down the biggest budget stories: the $1.588 trillion allocation, tourism boom, gold sector resurrection, cash grants debate, and what it all means for ordinary Guyanese trying to build wealth in the fastest-growing economy in the world.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: The Fugitive is Official, Budget Bonanza Continues, and Mia Mottley Goes for the Three-Peat</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-28-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Azruddin Mohamed is now officially Guyana&amp;rsquo;s Opposition Leader despite US indictments. Meanwhile, Budget 2026 promises keep rolling out and Barbados prepares for another Mottley landslide.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>The Guyana Daily Brief - Tuesday, January 27, 2026</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 aftermath: $1.588 trillion in promises, 15,000 house lots, a school for autistic children, and the opposition still can&amp;rsquo;t find the door to the National Assembly.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: DIS IS HOW YOU BUILD A NATION! Budget 2026 is HISTORIC!</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-27-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates Budget 2026 from Queens — praising the historic investments in housing, tourism, autism education, and agricultural development while wondering why opposition can&amp;rsquo;t find anything positive to say.</description></item><item><title>Friday Brief: US Ambassador Says Nadir Can Have His Opinion, APAD Warns Against Fugitive Opposition Leader, Tourism Minister Takes River Cruise</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-friday-brief/</guid><description>US Ambassador Theriot diplomatically sidesteps the Speaker drama, APAD joins the chorus against electing Mohamed, Minister Rodrigues cruises the Demerara, and over 200 Guyanese now certified in fibre optics. Plus opposition visits Tabatinga school and finds four workers.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Ambassador Theriot GETS IT, APAD Speaking FACTS, and River Cruises? This is PROGRESS!</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-01-23-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens applauds Ambassador Theriot&amp;rsquo;s diplomatic wisdom, celebrates APAD for putting country over politics, and explains why river cruises prove Guyana is becoming a REAL tourism destination.</description></item></channel></rss>