<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Jamaica on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/jamaica/</link><description>Recent content in Jamaica on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/jamaica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Heats Up, Trinidad PM Addresses Energy Week, Jamaica IMF Deal, and Cuba's Humanitarian Crisis Deepens</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with schools closing for election day, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM addresses Caribbean Energy Week, Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF $415M deal progresses, and Cuba&amp;rsquo;s crisis worsens as US tightens the screws.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: US Strikes Boats Near Venezuela, Jamaica Gets $415M Emergency IMF Loan, and T&amp;T Says Airspace is Fine</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US is blowing up boats in the Caribbean, Jamaica needs emergency cash after Hurricane Melissa, Trinidad says everything is normal (it&amp;#39;s not), and the T20 World Cup has kicked off.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, Barbados Election Heating Up, T&amp;T PM Blasts CARICOM, and Haiti Under Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF funds, Barbados gears up for February 11 election, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti&amp;rsquo;s leadership, and the T20 World Cup kicks off tomorrow. Your Caribbean regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — US Warships Still Blowing Up Boats, Barbados Heads to Polls, Jamaica Gets IMF Lifeline, and the Region Wonders What Happened to Sovereignty</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US military campaign in Caribbean waters has killed over 117 people, Barbados elections are 8 days away, Jamaica secured $415M in IMF emergency aid, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM praised the boat strikes, and CARICOM can&amp;rsquo;t agree on anything except that things are complicated.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Countdown, Trinidad's Police Scandal, and Carnival Season Heats Up</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with Mottley seeking a historic third term, Trinidad reels from CCTV footage of a police shooting, Carnival season kicks into high gear, and West Indies prep for T20 World Cup. Your regional Caribbean news roundup.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, US Tightens Visa Screws on Caribbean, and Trinidad Says 'We Didn't Do It'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF cash after Hurricane Melissa, the US cracks down on Caribbean birth tourism visas, and Trinidad keeps insisting it had nothing to do with the Venezuela operation. Your regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Daily Brief – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/caribbean-daily-brief-2026-01-31/</guid><description>IMF approves US$415M emergency aid for Jamaica, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, Venezuela aftermath reshaping regional travel, West Indies cricket, and more across the islands!</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your regional roundup from across the Caribbean&lt;/em> 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-jamaica-gets-us415-million-imf-emergency-loan">🇯🇲 Jamaica Gets US$415 Million IMF Emergency Loan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The IMF Executive Board has approved Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s request for emergency financial assistance of approximately &lt;strong>US$415 million&lt;/strong> to help meet urgent balance-of-payments needs. This comes as the region continues to navigate economic pressures from various global factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s Finance Minister is expected to outline how these funds will be deployed to stabilize the economy and protect vulnerable populations. The country has been a model for IMF structural adjustment programs in the past, but this emergency assistance signals ongoing challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Elections Feb 11, US Visa Crackdowns, Trinidad's AI Push, and Jamaica's IMF Return</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Regional roundup: Mia Mottley goes for third term, US tightens visa rules for pregnant travelers, Trinidad partners with Microsoft on AI, and Jamaica seeks IMF help again.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>US-Caribbean visa tensions, Jamaica&amp;#39;s IMF loan, Trinidad-US partnership, Venezuela oil law changes, and regional cricket updates</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Goes to Polls Feb 11, Trinidad's PM Kamla Warns About 'Divisiveness', Jamaica Gets $415M Hurricane Relief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley calls Barbados elections for February 11, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s new PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar navigates US-Venezuela tensions, Jamaica secures IMF emergency funding for Hurricane Melissa recovery, and Caribbean Airlines restructures its regional operations.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — January 21, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures US$6.7 billion for Hurricane Melissa recovery, Maduro claims presidency from Brooklyn jail, Haiti TPS termination hearing continues, and Trinidad welcomes new PM Stuart Young.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – January 20, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute tour of regional chaos, served with rum punch&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-the-maduro-situation-still-situating">🇻🇪 THE MADURO SITUATION: STILL SITUATING&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two weeks after Uncle Sam yoinked Nicolás Maduro out of Caracas like a bad tooth, the Caribbean is still dealing with the hangover. Thousands of tourists got stranded. Cruise ships played musical chairs in Barbados harbour. And Trinidad? Well, T&amp;amp;T said &amp;ldquo;sure ting&amp;rdquo; to letting U.S. military use their airports, which Venezuela called a betrayal. PM Kamla then spent the weekend cussing out the Energy Chamber for allegedly caring more about foreign oil companies than local contractors. Classic Trini Monday.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>