<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Venezuela on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/venezuela/</link><description>Recent content in Venezuela on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/venezuela/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – February 14, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-14-caribbean-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-14-caribbean-daily-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day across the Caribbean: Mia Mottley is in love with winning, the US Navy is in love with shooting boats, and Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM is about to sweet-talk an energy conference. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-mia-mottley-sweeps-barbados--again">🇧🇧 MIA MOTTLEY SWEEPS BARBADOS — AGAIN&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Barbados Prime Minister Mia Mottley has won every single seat in Parliament — for the third consecutive election. She is now only the second Caribbean leader in history to achieve a 30-0 sweep three times, joining former Grenada PM Dr. Keith Mitchell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wednesday's Guyana Brief - Corruption Score: We Moved ONE Point, 30 Contractors Blacklisted, and the Flag That Started a War</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-11-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-11-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Guyana crawls up ONE spot on the corruption index, 30 contractors get blacklisted, Ali tours Brazil&amp;rsquo;s gas plant, sugar promises continue, and the Guyana flag at the Super Bowl has people HEATED.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: US Strikes Boats Near Venezuela, Jamaica Gets $415M Emergency IMF Loan, and T&amp;T Says Airspace is Fine</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US is blowing up boats in the Caribbean, Jamaica needs emergency cash after Hurricane Melissa, Trinidad says everything is normal (it&amp;#39;s not), and the T20 World Cup has kicked off.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Brief: Exxon Now Owns ALL Four Oil Ships, Finance Minister Drops Pablo Escobar Reference, and a Miracle Baby at GPHC</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</guid><description>ExxonMobil completes its FPSO collection like Pokémon cards, Dr. Singh invokes Pablo Escobar in Parliament, GPHC doctors save mother and baby from a rare bleeding disorder, and the Opposition Leader says the budget won&amp;#39;t lift anyone out of poverty. Happy Sunday, Guyana.</description></item><item><title>Friday's Guyana Brief - Venezuela Still Scary, MP Falls in Parliament, 53,000 Weed Plants Burned, and the Budget Debate Rolls On Like a Runaway Canter</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-friday-brief/</guid><description>President Ali tells the army &amp;lsquo;don&amp;rsquo;t blink&amp;rsquo; on Venezuela, an MP fractures her ankle falling in Parliament, police burn 53,000 cannabis plants in Linden, Kaieteur calls the budget &amp;lsquo;matchless propaganda,&amp;rsquo; and Dem Boys Seh more road just means more traffic. Your 5-minute Friday news circus.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take: The President Standing Strong While They Nitpick Everything</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens breaks down why President Ali&amp;rsquo;s GDF speech was exactly what Guyana needed, the budget debate critics have no alternative plan, tourism is booming, and the opposition should stop complaining and start contributing.</description></item><item><title>☕ Sunday Brief: Budget Debate Opens Monday, Cement Truck Kills on Demerara Bridge, and the Government Discovers 'Late Movers' Advantage'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-sunday-brief/</guid><description>Budget 2026 debate starts Monday while Finance Minister discovers Guyana has a &amp;rsquo;late movers&amp;rsquo; advantage&amp;rsquo; in oil. Meanwhile, an unlicensed driver kills someone on the Demerara Bridge and the opposition says Tabatinga school is nowhere near ready. Your 5-minute Sunday news circus.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, US Tightens Visa Screws on Caribbean, and Trinidad Says 'We Didn't Do It'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF cash after Hurricane Melissa, the US cracks down on Caribbean birth tourism visas, and Trinidad keeps insisting it had nothing to do with the Venezuela operation. Your regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Mottley's Three-Peat, US Visa Crackdowns, and Airlines in Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11, Caribbean faces stricter US visa rules, and airlines are cutting routes left and right.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>US-Caribbean visa tensions, Jamaica&amp;#39;s IMF loan, Trinidad-US partnership, Venezuela oil law changes, and regional cricket updates</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — January 21, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures US$6.7 billion for Hurricane Melissa recovery, Maduro claims presidency from Brooklyn jail, Haiti TPS termination hearing continues, and Trinidad welcomes new PM Stuart Young.</description></item><item><title>☕ Monday Brief: Former Finance Minister Admits Exxon Exploited Us, Venezuela Border Watch, and Pay-To-Party Culture</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-monday-brief/</guid><description>Winston Jordan finally admits what everyone knew, PM Phillips says troops are ready for anything Venezuelan, and birthday parties now cost admission.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh Responds: Jordan Finally Talking Truth, Border Security Strong, and Mash Coming!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-19-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh sets the record straight on who really signed that oil contract, praises border vigilance, and gets ready for Republic Day.</description></item></channel></rss>