<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Haiti on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/haiti/</link><description>Recent content in Haiti on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/haiti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, Barbados Election Heating Up, T&amp;T PM Blasts CARICOM, and Haiti Under Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF funds, Barbados gears up for February 11 election, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti&amp;rsquo;s leadership, and the T20 World Cup kicks off tomorrow. Your Caribbean regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — January 21, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures US$6.7 billion for Hurricane Melissa recovery, Maduro claims presidency from Brooklyn jail, Haiti TPS termination hearing continues, and Trinidad welcomes new PM Stuart Young.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – January 20, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your 5-minute tour of regional chaos, served with rum punch&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-the-maduro-situation-still-situating">🇻🇪 THE MADURO SITUATION: STILL SITUATING&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two weeks after Uncle Sam yoinked Nicolás Maduro out of Caracas like a bad tooth, the Caribbean is still dealing with the hangover. Thousands of tourists got stranded. Cruise ships played musical chairs in Barbados harbour. And Trinidad? Well, T&amp;amp;T said &amp;ldquo;sure ting&amp;rdquo; to letting U.S. military use their airports, which Venezuela called a betrayal. PM Kamla then spent the weekend cussing out the Energy Chamber for allegedly caring more about foreign oil companies than local contractors. Classic Trini Monday.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>