<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Diaspora on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/diaspora/</link><description>Recent content in Diaspora on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/diaspora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: 'ONE Point? That's PROGRESS, Beta!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-11-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-11-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the corruption index improvement, explains why 30 blacklisted contractors proves the government is WORKING, and has strong opinions about the Guyana flag at the Super Bowl.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take: The President Standing Strong While They Nitpick Everything</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens breaks down why President Ali&amp;rsquo;s GDF speech was exactly what Guyana needed, the budget debate critics have no alternative plan, tourism is booming, and the opposition should stop complaining and start contributing.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Thursday Response — 'This Government Building the Future While Opposition Playing Victim'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle (and the other papers) from Queens and explains why the PPP is building the future while the opposition focuses on everything except solutions.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: 'Budget 2026 Is What Development Looks Like — Take Notes!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the papers independently and finds plenty to celebrate: Budget 2026&amp;rsquo;s massive investments, a fancy new Georgetown hotel, record tourism numbers, and the UK rolling out the red carpet for Guyana. The opposition? Still complaining.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh: Budget 2026 Is a Masterclass, the Development Bank Is Revolutionary, and the Brief Needs an Economics Lesson</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle, celebrates Budget 2026 and the new Development Bank, and wonders why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t see progress when it&amp;rsquo;s staring them in the face.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh Responds – Saturday, January 31, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-31/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/uncle-ramesh-2026-01-31/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh breaks down Budget 2026, the UK climate partnership, ExxonMobil&amp;#39;s production records, and reminds you WHY the PPP is the best thing since cook-up rice.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>A Pro-Government Perspective from Queens, NY&lt;/em> 🗽🇬🇾&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="nephew-and-niece-dem">Nephew and Niece Dem,&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Greetings from Queens where the cold biting but my heart warm from reading about all the good things happening back home!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me tell you, I just finish reading through the Budget 2026 details and I nearly fall off me chair with joy! &lt;strong>$1.558 TRILLION dollars!&lt;/strong> That is the biggest budget in Guyana history! And what the critics have to say? &amp;ldquo;Rich getting richer.&amp;rdquo; Eh-eh! When the country was poor and nothing wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening, dem same people was complaining. Now we building and spending, and dem still complaining!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Response: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>A diaspora perspective from Queens, NY — celebrating Budget 2026, Barama&amp;#39;s billion-dollar investment, and decisive government action</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh: Speaker Nadir Speaking FACTS, Opposition Should Thank Him for the Warning</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens applauds Speaker Nadir for telling the truth about the Opposition Leader situation, explains why the Belgian port deal proves Guyana is the Caribbean&amp;rsquo;s rising star, and questions why Charrandass is making TikToks instead of reading laws.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: 'Finally Somebody Standing Up for Democracy!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates the Opposition Leader election announcement, defends Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s garbage situation, and explains why solar power proves the PPP is the best thing since sliced bread.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Progress Despite the Noise</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens explains why the Opposition Leader delay is actually democracy at work, the Police Academy scandal is opposition propaganda, and Georgetown garbage is a City Hall problem.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Sustainable Governance, Not Reckless Giveaways</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-20-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>From Queens, New York — Where we understand fiscal responsibility&lt;/em> 🇬🇾🗽&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="greetings-from-the-diaspora">Greetings from the Diaspora!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ah, another day, another set of headlines from Guyana that the critics want to twist into something negative. But Uncle Ramesh here to set the record straight for all my fellow Guyanese overseas who want to understand what&amp;rsquo;s REALLY happening in we homeland.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-on-cash-grants-responsible-leadership">💰 ON CASH GRANTS: RESPONSIBLE LEADERSHIP&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So the President said cash grants are &amp;ldquo;not sustainable,&amp;rdquo; and suddenly everybody vex? Let me ask you something: which responsible government just keeps handing out money without a plan?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Hotels Mean JOBS, Women Cricketers Making Us PROUD, and Stop Complaining!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-18-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Women&amp;rsquo;s T20 squad, defends the hotel boom, explains why digital health records are PROGRESS, and asks why the Brief can&amp;rsquo;t just be happy for once.</description></item><item><title>Dr. Sharmila Persaud: From Berbice to Brain Surgery</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-16-patriots-portfolio-dr-persaud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>A Weekly Profile of Guyanese Excellence&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore, Dr. Sharmila Persaud is performing some of the world&amp;rsquo;s most complex brain surgeries. But every morning, she looks at a photo on her desk: her grandmother&amp;rsquo;s wooden house in Berbice, where she grew up without electricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-journey">The Journey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;People ask me how I got from there to here,&amp;rdquo; Dr. Persaud says, gesturing around her state-of-the-art operating suite. &amp;ldquo;I tell them: I got here because I started there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>