<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Politics on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>☕ The Daily Brief – Tuesday, February 17, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-17-tuesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-17-tuesday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader arrested for being 35 minutes late to court. An NCN cameraman brought a gun to the same court. Hakeem Olajuwon wants to sell you a condo for US$150K. Stabroek News mourning continues. Ali wants a 6-week health campaign. And the US just blew up another boat in the Caribbean.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Uncle Ramesh Responds – Tuesday, February 17, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-17-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-17-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle from Queens and sets the record straight on Energy Conference, telemedicine, airports, health campaign, and Hakeem Olajuwon&amp;rsquo;s investment in Guyana.</description></item><item><title>☕ The Daily Brief – Friday, February 13, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-13-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-13-daily-brief/</guid><description>Stabroek News announces closure after 39 years. Georgetown swamped by 4-inch rainfall. Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s cambio evidence mounts. Mottley wins AGAIN. Oil boom stealing police officers. And rockets are launching from our backyard.</description></item><item><title>Monday Brief: Auditor General Goes Silent While Billions Vanish, 77 Cubans Screened for Trafficking, and Hetmyer Breaks a World Cup Record</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</guid><description>Christopher Ram questions whether the Auditor General is actually auditing anything, 77 Cubans are screened for suspected human trafficking, more than 20 homes bulldozed in Circuitville, and Hetmyer smashes the fastest WI fifty in T20 World Cup history.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Two Guyanese Boys Own de World Cup, But de Brief Want Talk About Auditor General</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates Hetmyer and Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s World Cup heroics, praises the Bayroc Stadium opening, and wonders why the Brief is obsessed with Christopher Ram.</description></item><item><title>De Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your daily dose of Guyanese news, served with a side of pepper sauce&lt;/em> 🌶️&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-gra-officers-getting-lock-up-over-azruddin-mohameds-fancy-cars">💰 GRA Officers Getting Lock Up Over Azruddin Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s Fancy Cars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, well, well&amp;hellip; remember how everybody was wondering how certain vehicles was getting through customs smoother than a greased-up mango seed? The Guyana Revenue Authority done fire several officers and now they heading to court for AML/CFT violations connected to transferring vehicles from our favourite US-sanctioned businessman, Azruddin Mohamed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Daily Brief: Saturday, January 24, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-24-daily-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader drama continues, Budget 2026 incoming, Barama drops $1 billion, and INTERPOL busts gold smuggling ring</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: 'Finally Somebody Standing Up for Democracy!'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh celebrates the Opposition Leader election announcement, defends Georgetown&amp;rsquo;s garbage situation, and explains why solar power proves the PPP is the best thing since sliced bread.</description></item><item><title>Wednesday Brief: Opposition Leader Monday Showdown, Solar Power for Linden, and Georgetown's Garbage Emergency</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-21-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Speaker Nadir finally schedules Opposition Leader vote for Monday while calling candidate an &amp;lsquo;international fugitive.&amp;rsquo; Plus: Linden gets solar farms, Georgetown drowning in garbage, and the Mohameds saga continues. Your 5-minute news circus.</description></item><item><title>🔍 [CRITICAL] Wednesday Brief: Guyanese Takes IICA Helm, Census Controversy, and Cybercrime Crackdown</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-wednesday-brief/</guid><description>Muhammad Ibrahim becomes IICA Director-General, census data sparks housing debate, cybercrime law faces criticism, and AG slams courts for ignoring legislation.</description></item><item><title>😊 [PRO-GOV] Uncle Ramesh: When De Government Does De Math Right (For Once)</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-uncle-ramesh-take/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-15-uncle-ramesh-take/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh does the math on the census data and discovers the government was actually planning ahead. Who knew? Plus, finally some people heading to jail.</description></item><item><title>The Mohamed Saga: A Family, An Empire, and Guyana's Tangled Web</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/magazine/magazine-mohamed-saga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/magazine/magazine-mohamed-saga/</guid><description>The Mohamed family went from sanction targets to courtroom celebrities. This is the full story of how one family&amp;rsquo;s business empire became the center of Guyana&amp;rsquo;s biggest political controversy.</description></item><item><title>Jagdeo's Silence: The Political Strategy Behind Saying Nothing</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/magazine/magazine-jagdeo-silence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/magazine/magazine-jagdeo-silence/</guid><description>Vice President Bharrat Jagdeo hasn&amp;rsquo;t held a press conference in three weeks. For a politician known for weekly media briefings, his sudden silence speaks volumes. We investigate what&amp;rsquo;s really happening behind closed doors.</description></item></channel></rss>