<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Government on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/government/</link><description>Recent content in Government on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: Mortgages, Nurses, and the Brief's Selective Memory</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-16-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh is a retired accountant from Berbice, now living in Queens, New York. He reads the papers — especially the Chronicle — and provides his perspective.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Monday morning and the Brief leading with Azruddin showing up late. That&amp;rsquo;s the headline? A man who is US-indicted, facing extradition, and can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to arrive on time to his own hearing — and the Brief treating it like comedy instead of asking why the Opposition Leader has such contempt for the judicial process?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Responds: The Government Building, Not Destroying — Read the Chronicle, Not the Obituaries</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-15-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Uncle Ramesh is a retired accountant from Berbice, now living in Queens, New York. He reads the papers himself — especially the Chronicle — and responds to the Brief&amp;rsquo;s coverage with his own perspective. He is unapologetically pro-government when the government deserves it.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Alright, alright. Everybody crying about Stabroek News like the whole country falling apart. You know what else happened this weekend? &lt;strong>A US$120 million training college opened in Port Mourant.&lt;/strong> Thirty-five young Guyanese already working offshore. Certified. Employed. Earning real money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>📊 Weekly Progress Report: February 5-11, 2026</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-11-progress-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-11-progress-report/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s government achievements: Budget 2026 approvals rolling through Committee of Supply, Gas-to-Energy at 68%, new Amerindian hostel funded, recycling centre launched, and 30 bad contractors blacklisted.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Cyaan See Progress If Yuh Put Blindfold Pon Dem Eye'</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-03-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle cover to cover, watches the budget debate livestream from Queens, and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition opened with a gold-smuggling MP demanding mining transparency.</description></item></channel></rss>