<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>T20-World-Cup on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/t20-world-cup/</link><description>Recent content in T20-World-Cup on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/tags/t20-world-cup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monday Brief: Auditor General Goes Silent While Billions Vanish, 77 Cubans Screened for Trafficking, and Hetmyer Breaks a World Cup Record</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-monday-brief/</guid><description>Christopher Ram questions whether the Auditor General is actually auditing anything, 77 Cubans are screened for suspected human trafficking, more than 20 homes bulldozed in Circuitville, and Hetmyer smashes the fastest WI fifty in T20 World Cup history.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh Take: Two Guyanese Boys Own de World Cup, But de Brief Want Talk About Auditor General</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates Hetmyer and Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s World Cup heroics, praises the Bayroc Stadium opening, and wonders why the Brief is obsessed with Christopher Ram.</description></item><item><title>🇬🇾 Saturday Brief: Opposition Leader Rips Budget, Secret Extradition Revealed, and Linden Gets a Stadium</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-saturday-brief/</guid><description>Opposition Leader Mohamed delivers maiden budget speech and it&amp;rsquo;s a SCORCHER, a secret US extradition request surfaces, Linden opens its shiny new stadium, Ali promises miners the moon (if they declare their gold), and the Windies take on Scotland in the T20 World Cup opener.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item><item><title>👴🏾 Uncle Ramesh: Stadium Opening Day! PROGRESS You Can TOUCH! While Opposition Leader Talks Nonsense!</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh from Queens celebrates the Bayroc Stadium opening, praises Ali&amp;rsquo;s mining support package, and has STRONG words about the Opposition Leader&amp;rsquo;s maiden speech.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, Barbados Election Heating Up, T&amp;T PM Blasts CARICOM, and Haiti Under Fire</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-06-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF funds, Barbados gears up for February 11 election, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti&amp;rsquo;s leadership, and the T20 World Cup kicks off tomorrow. Your Caribbean regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>☕ Wednesday Brief: Budget Day 2 Turns Into WWE SmackDown, Speaker Nadir's Press Crackdown Gets EVERYBODY Vex, and the Oil Fund About to Get US$2.8 Billion It Won't Keep</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget Day 2 delivers absolute chaos as government and opposition clash over everything from sugar to Amerindians. Speaker Nadir&amp;rsquo;s media lockout draws fire from every direction. The Oil Fund expects US$2.8B this year — and critics say it&amp;rsquo;ll disappear just as fast. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, 9 million carbon credits, and the T20 World Cup starts Friday.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election ONE WEEK Away, T20 World Cup Starts Friday, and the US Still Patrolling Caribbean Waters Like It's Their Pool</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados votes in 7 days with 93 candidates and Mottley going for a third term. The T20 World Cup starts Friday in India with West Indies facing Scotland. US military operations in the Caribbean continue dividing the region. Plus: Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF lifeline, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s police shooting scandal, and the CCJ President visits Barbados.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Scripts — Wednesday, February 4, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-youtube-scripts/</guid><description>60-second and 4-minute HeyGen-ready scripts for Wednesday February 4, 2026.</description></item></channel></rss>