<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Regional News on The Guyana Brief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/categories/regional-news/</link><description>Recent content in Regional News on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</url><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guyanadailybrief.com/categories/regional-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Heats Up, Trinidad PM Addresses Energy Week, Jamaica IMF Deal, and Cuba's Humanitarian Crisis Deepens</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-09-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with schools closing for election day, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM addresses Caribbean Energy Week, Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF $415M deal progresses, and Cuba&amp;rsquo;s crisis worsens as US tightens the screws.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Trinidad Carnival EXPLODES, Barbados Election in 4 Days, Jamaica IMF Rescue, and Windies Open T20 Campaign</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-07-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Trinidad Carnival kicks off TODAY, Barbados heads to polls February 11, Jamaica takes $415M IMF emergency loan, West Indies open T20 World Cup vs Scotland, and US tightens visa screws on Caribbean nationals.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — Barbados Election Next Week, Jamaica Gets IMF Emergency Cash, T&amp;T PM Slams CARICOM, and US Visa Crackdown Continues</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-05-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados goes to the polls February 11th, Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency assistance, Trinidad PM doubles down on CARICOM criticism, CARICOM rebukes Haiti leadership, US tightens visa scrutiny across the region, and Caribbean tourism takes a hit.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election ONE WEEK Away, T20 World Cup Starts Friday, and the US Still Patrolling Caribbean Waters Like It's Their Pool</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-04-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados votes in 7 days with 93 candidates and Mottley going for a third term. The T20 World Cup starts Friday in India with West Indies facing Scotland. US military operations in the Caribbean continue dividing the region. Plus: Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s IMF lifeline, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s police shooting scandal, and the CCJ President visits Barbados.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief — US Warships Still Blowing Up Boats, Barbados Heads to Polls, Jamaica Gets IMF Lifeline, and the Region Wonders What Happened to Sovereignty</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-03-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>The US military campaign in Caribbean waters has killed over 117 people, Barbados elections are 8 days away, Jamaica secured $415M in IMF emergency aid, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s PM praised the boat strikes, and CARICOM can&amp;rsquo;t agree on anything except that things are complicated.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Countdown, Trinidad's Police Scandal, and Carnival Season Heats Up</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-02-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11 with Mottley seeking a historic third term, Trinidad reels from CCTV footage of a police shooting, Carnival season kicks into high gear, and West Indies prep for T20 World Cup. Your regional Caribbean news roundup.</description></item><item><title>🌴 Caribbean Brief: Jamaica Gets $415M IMF Lifeline, US Tightens Visa Screws on Caribbean, and Trinidad Says 'We Didn't Do It'</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-02-01-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures emergency IMF cash after Hurricane Melissa, the US cracks down on Caribbean birth tourism visas, and Trinidad keeps insisting it had nothing to do with the Venezuela operation. Your regional roundup.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Daily Brief – Wednesday, January 29, 2026</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-29-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Your regional roundup from across the Caribbean&lt;/em> 🌴&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="-jamaica-gets-us415-million-imf-emergency-loan">🇯🇲 Jamaica Gets US$415 Million IMF Emergency Loan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The IMF Executive Board has approved Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s request for emergency financial assistance of approximately &lt;strong>US$415 million&lt;/strong> to help meet urgent balance-of-payments needs. This comes as the region continues to navigate economic pressures from various global factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s Finance Minister is expected to outline how these funds will be deployed to stabilize the economy and protect vulnerable populations. The country has been a model for IMF structural adjustment programs in the past, but this emergency assistance signals ongoing challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Mottley's Three-Peat, US Visa Crackdowns, and Airlines in Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-28-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Barbados heads to polls February 11, Caribbean faces stricter US visa rules, and airlines are cutting routes left and right.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Weekly Roundup: IMF Bailout for Jamaica, US Visa Crackdown, and Caribbean Airlines Chaos</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-27-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Jamaica secures $415M IMF emergency funds, Caribbean Airlines closes Barbados hub, US cracks down on birth tourism across the region, and Venezuela conflict ripples through Caribbean tourism.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Elections Feb 11, US Visa Crackdowns, Trinidad's AI Push, and Jamaica's IMF Return</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-26-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Regional roundup: Mia Mottley goes for third term, US tightens visa rules for pregnant travelers, Trinidad partners with Microsoft on AI, and Jamaica seeks IMF help again.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Election Feb 11, Trinidad PM Kamla Navigates CARICOM, Caribbean Airlines Restructures</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-23-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>PM Mottley calls snap election for February 11 seeking historic third term, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s Kamla Persad-Bissessar defends CARICOM stance, and Caribbean Airlines closes its Barbados hub.</description></item><item><title>Caribbean Brief: Barbados Goes to Polls Feb 11, Trinidad's PM Kamla Warns About 'Divisiveness', Jamaica Gets $415M Hurricane Relief</title><link>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://guyanadailybrief.com/posts/2026-01-22-caribbean-brief/</guid><description>Mottley calls Barbados elections for February 11, Trinidad&amp;rsquo;s new PM Kamla Persad-Bissessar navigates US-Venezuela tensions, Jamaica secures IMF emergency funding for Hurricane Melissa recovery, and Caribbean Airlines restructures its regional operations.</description></item></channel></rss>