<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Education on The Guyana Brief</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on The Guyana Brief</description><image><title>The Guyana Brief</title><url>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</url><link>http://localhost:1313/images/social-share.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speedeet &amp; Wilar: The Biggest Ship in the Sea</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-speedeet-wilar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-speedeet-wilar/</guid><description>Speedeet and Wilar visit the waterfront and learn about the giant ships pumping Guyana&amp;#39;s oil — and ask the questions that matter.</description></item><item><title>Sunday Brief: Exxon Now Owns ALL Four Oil Ships, Finance Minister Drops Pablo Escobar Reference, and a Miracle Baby at GPHC</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-08-sunday-brief/</guid><description>ExxonMobil completes its FPSO collection like Pokémon cards, Dr. Singh invokes Pablo Escobar in Parliament, GPHC doctors save mother and baby from a rare bleeding disorder, and the Opposition Leader says the budget won&amp;#39;t lift anyone out of poverty. Happy Sunday, Guyana.</description></item><item><title>☕ Wednesday Brief: Budget Day 2 Turns Into WWE SmackDown, Speaker Nadir's Press Crackdown Gets EVERYBODY Vex, and the Oil Fund About to Get US$2.8 Billion It Won't Keep</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-daily-brief/</guid><description>Budget Day 2 delivers absolute chaos as government and opposition clash over everything from sugar to Amerindians. Speaker Nadir&amp;rsquo;s media lockout draws fire from every direction. The Oil Fund expects US$2.8B this year — and critics say it&amp;rsquo;ll disappear just as fast. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, 9 million carbon credits, and the T20 World Cup starts Friday.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Ramesh's Take — 'Dem Got a Plan fuh Everything and All Dem Could Do is Complain!'</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2026-02-04-uncle-ramesh/</guid><description>Uncle Ramesh reads the Chronicle and can&amp;rsquo;t believe the opposition still complaining while the government delivering 53,000 house lots, 9 million carbon credits, and a five-year sugar plan. Plus: Panama opening an embassy, Lady Jags scoring 14 goals, and Minister Browne put Dawn Hastings in she place.</description></item></channel></rss>